<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Atypon//DTD Atypon Systems Journal Archiving and Interchange NLM DTD v3.0.0 20090430//EN" "atypon-archivearticle3.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">connect</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">connect</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title xml:lang="en">QScience Connect</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="ppub">2223-506X</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">37</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5339/connect.2013.37</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					<subject>Research article</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Effect of estradiol-17β on serum mineral concentrations of female Japanese quail</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
				<contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
					<string-name>
						<given-names>Hüseyin B.</given-names>
						<x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
						<surname>Çiftci</surname>
					</string-name>
					
						<sup>*</sup>
					
				<x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
				</contrib>
				<contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
					<string-name>
						<given-names>Iskender</given-names>
						<x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
						<surname>Yıldırım</surname>
					</string-name>
				</contrib>
				<aff id="aff1">
					<sup>1</sup>Department of Animal Science, School of Agriculture, Selçuk University, Konya 42075, Turkey. </aff>
			</contrib-group>
			<author-notes>
				<corresp id="c1">
					<sup>*</sup>Email: hbciftci@selcuk.edu.tr</corresp>
			</author-notes>
			<pub-date pub-type="pub">
				<day>25</day>
				<month>8</month>
				<year>2013</year>
			</pub-date>
			<issue content-type="issue-sequence">2013</issue>
			<elocation-id>37</elocation-id>
			<history>
				<date date-type="received">
					<day>21</day>
					<month>8</month>
					<year>2013</year>
				</date>
				<date date-type="accepted">
					<day>13</day>
					<month>9</month>
					<year>2013</year>
				</date>
			</history>
			<permissions>
				<copyright-statement>© 2013 Çiftci, Yıldırım, licensee Bloomsbury Qatar
Foundation Journals. This is an open access article distributed under the terms
of the Creative Commons Attribution License CC BY 3.0 which permits
unrestricted use, distribution and reproduction in any medium, provided the
original work is properly cited.</copyright-statement>
				<copyright-year>2013</copyright-year>
				<copyright-holder>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals</copyright-holder>
			</permissions>
			<self-uri content-type="pdf" xlink:href="connect.2013.37.pdf" xlink:type="simple"></self-uri>
			<abstract abstract-type="graphical">
				<title>Abstract</title>
				<p>Minerals have a profound impact on reproduction. The relations between estradiol-17β (E<sub>2</sub>) and blood mineral levels have been studied mainly in human and rats, not quail. Therefore, the aim of this study was to test the effect of E<sub>2</sub> on serum mineral concentrations in Japanese quail (Coturnix japonica). The study was conducted at the Seljuk University animal farm thirteen week old female Japanese quails (n=33) were housed in cages (25x35x48 cm) under a 16 hours light: 8 hours dark cycle. During the course of the study, birds were fed ad libitum with a diet supplying 20% crude protein, 2901 kcal/kg metabolic energy, 2.5% calcium (Ca), 0.35% phosphorus (P), 1.02% lysine, 1.02% methionine and cysteine mixture. After a 7-day adaptation period, the birds were randomly assigned to 3 groups, one control (n=10) and two others as test groups (n=11 and n=12). Birds in test groups were subcutaneously injected with 0.1 or 0.2 mg E<sub>2</sub>. Blood samples were collected from the jugular vein and serum mineral concentrations were measured by HNO<sub>3</sub> digestion method. Injection of 0.2 mg E<sub>2</sub> resulted with a significant reduction in serum potassium concentration as compared to control group. Injection of 0.2 mg E<sub>2</sub> caused a significant reduction in serum iron concentration as compared to 0.1 mg E<sub>2</sub> injected group. Injection of 0.1 mg E<sub>2</sub> caused a significant increase in serum chromium concentration over the control. Serum boron concentration was significantly high after the injection of 0.1 or 0.2 mg E<sub>2</sub> over the control group.  Effect of E<sub>2</sub> on serum mineral concentration depends on injection dose. An injection of 0.1 or 0.2 mg E<sub>2</sub> significantly increased serum boron concentration, which is an indication for the effect of E<sub>2</sub> on bone mineralization and feed conversion ratio. Thus, administration of boron or E<sub>2</sub> may protect postmenopausal women against osteoporosis and estradiol can be employed for the treatment of osteoporosis. Injection of 0.1 mg E<sub>2</sub> caused a significant increase in serum chromium concentration, which indicates the function of E<sub>2</sub> on body growth and reproductive performance. Injection of 0.2 mg E<sub>2</sub> caused significant reduction in serum potassium (K) concentration, while there was a slight increase in serum sodium (Na) concentration. This indicates the involvement of E<sub>2</sub> in rennin-angiotensin-aldosterone system.
				</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
</article>
