<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Atypon//DTD Atypon Systems Journal Archiving and Interchange NLM DTD v3.0.0 20090430//EN" "atypon-archivearticle3.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article">
<front>
<journal-meta> 
<journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">connect</journal-id> 
<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">connect</journal-id> 
<journal-title-group> 
<journal-title>QScience Connect</journal-title> 
</journal-title-group> 
<issn pub-type="ppub">2223-506X</issn> 
<publisher> 
<publisher-name>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals</publisher-name> </publisher> 
</journal-meta> 
<article-meta> 
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">3</article-id> 
<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5339/connect.2011.3</article-id> 
<article-categories> 
<subj-group subj-group-type="heading"> 
<subject>Research
article</subject> 
</subj-group> 
</article-categories> 
<title-group> 
<article-title>Distribution of non-marine diatoms in surface sediments of streams in Socotra Island, Yemen</article-title> 

<trans-title-group  xml:lang="AR">
<trans-title>توزيع الدياتومات الغير بحرية في الرواسب السطحية الحديثة في بعض وديان جزيرة   
سقطرى –
</trans-title>
</trans-title-group>
</title-group> 
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<string-name>         
<given-names>Abdelfattah A.</given-names>
<x> </x>              
<surname>Zalat</surname>  </string-name> 
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>
<x><sup>,</sup></x> <xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN3"><sup>3</sup></xref>              
<x> and  </x></contrib>   
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<string-name>               
<given-names>Mohammed
A.</given-names>
<x> </x>                
<surname>Al-Wosabi</surname>  </string-name> 
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>
<x><sup>,</sup></x> 
<xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c1"><sup>&#x204E;</sup></xref>                
<x> </x></contrib> 
<aff id="aff1"><sup>1</sup>Hodiedah University, Faculty of
Marine and Environmental Science, Marine Geology Department, Hodeidah,
Yemen</aff> 
<aff id="aff2"><sup>2</sup>Sana&#x2019;a University, Faculty of Science, Earth and Environmental Sciences
Department, Sana&#x2019;a, Yemen <!--\newline ~\\[-5pt]--></aff></contrib-group>

<author-notes> 
<corresp id="c1"><sup>&#x204E;</sup>Corresponding author. Tel.: 00967 777650710. E-mail: ma_wosabi@yahoo.com</corresp> 
<fn id="FN3">
<label><sup>3</sup></label>
<p>E-mail: abzalat@yahoo.com</p></fn>

<fn id="FN4">
<label>Academic Editor: </label>
<p>Dr.&#x00A0;Habib&#x00A0;Alimohammadian,
Geological Survey of Iran, Iran</p></fn>

</author-notes> 




<pub-date pub-type="pub"> 
<day>18</day> 
<month>11</month> 
<year>2011</year> </pub-date> 
<issue content-type="issue-sequence">2011</issue> 
<elocation-id>3</elocation-id>
<history> 
<date date-type="received">
<day>29</day>
<month>6</month>
<year>2011</year></date> 
<date date-type="accepted">
<day>06</day>
<month>10</month>
<year>2011</year></date></history>
<permissions> 
<copyright-statement>&#x00A9;&#x00A0;2011 Zalat &#x0026; Al-Wosabi, licensee Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation
Journals. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the
Creative Commons Attribution License CC BY 3.0 which permits unrestricted
use, distribution and reproduction in any medium, provided the original
work is properly cited.</copyright-statement> 
<copyright-year>2011</copyright-year> 
<copyright-holder>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals</copyright-holder> </permissions>
<self-uri content-type="pdf" xlink:href="connect.2011.3.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
<abstract>
<title>Abstract</title>
<p>Abundance and species composition of non-marine benthic diatom assemblages were studied from surface sediments samples of&#x00A0;11 streams distributed in Socotra Island, located in the northwest Indian Ocean. A total of&#x00A0;145 diatom species, representing&#x00A0;44 genera, were identified. The overall diatom communities appear to be the first recorded off the island. Pennales and non-planktonic taxa were most dominant over centrales and planktonic forms, both in diversity of genera and species. The majority of recognized diatoms are of cosmopolitan distribution. The predominant diatom flora in the surface sediment samples follow: 
<italic>Synedra ulna, Synedra longissima, Encyonema caespitosum, Encyonema silesiacum, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Mastogloia braunii, Mastogloia dansei, Mastogloia elliptica, Navicula cryptocephala, Navicula cryptotenella, Navicula rhynchocephala, Navicula cincta, Nitzschia amphibian, Nitzschia frustulum, Nitzschia perminuta, Cocconeis placentula, Pleurosira laevis and Staurosirella pinnata</italic>. These are found in addition to the common occurrence of 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis, Amphora Montana, Anomoeoneis sphaerophora, Cyclotella meneghiniana, Cymbella affinis, Diploneis elliptica, Encyonema mesianum, Diploneis smithii, Gomphonema gracile, Gomphonema parvulum, Kobayasia subtilissima, Mastogloia smithii, Navicula minuscule, Navicula notha, Navicula tenelloides, Nitzschia obtuse, Nitzschia palea, Nitzschia scalaris, Synedra nana, Tryblionella acuminate, Tryblionella granulate</italic> and 
<italic>Tryblionella punctata</italic>. Multivariate statistical techniques including detrended correspondence and cluster analyses were used to summarize changes in the diatom assemblages present in the examined streams. The results indicated six major diatom assemblages with a variation in dominant species. Each assemblage reflects distinctive environmental conditions based on salinity preference of the recognized and dominant.</p></abstract>

<trans-abstract xml:lang="AR"><title>الملخّص</title>
<p>
    تعتبر هذه الدراسة هي الأولى من نوعها على رسوبيات جزيرة سقطرى والتي تم فيها دراسة تواجد وتركيب الدياتومات التي تم استخلاصها من الرسوبيات السطحية الحديثة والتي جمعت من 11 واديا مائيا في جزيرة سقطرى الواقعة في الجزء الشمالي الغربي للمحيط الهندي. أمكن تعريف 145 نوعا من الدياتومات التي تنتمي إلى 44  جنسا. 
</p>
<p>
إن الأنواع التي تم تعريفها تمثل فيها الدياتومات القاعية الريشية أكثر من الدياتومات المركزية الطافية، وتعتبر تلك الأنواع من الأنواع ذات التوزيع العالمي. كان هناك تفاوت في نسبة تواجد الأنواع بشكل ملحوظ ولكن كانت الأنواع الأكثر وفرة هي:
</p>
<p>
 Synedra ulna, Synedra longissima, Encyonema caespitosum, Encyonema silesiacum, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Mastogloia braunii, Mastogloia dansei, Mastogloia elliptica, Navicula cryptocephala. Navicula cryptotenella, Navicula rhynchocephala, Navicula cincta, Nitzschia amphibian, Nitzschia frustulum, Nitzschia perminuta, Cocconeis placentula, Pleurosira laevis, Staurosirella pinnata.
</p>
<p> 
أما الأنواع المسجلة بأعداد شائعة فهي:
</p>
<p>
Amphora coffeaeformis, Amphora Montana, Anomoeoneis sphaerophora, Cyclotella meneghiniana, Cymbella affinis, Diploneis elliptica, Encyonema mesianum, Diploneis smithii, Gomphonema gracile, Gomphonema parvulum, Kobayasia subtilissima, Mastogloia smithii, Navicula minuscule, Navicula notha, Navicula tenelloides, Nitzschia obtuse, Nitzschia  palea, Nitzschia  scalaris, Synedra nana, Tryblionella acuminate, Tryblionella granulate and Tryblionella punctata.
</p>
<p>
    أظهرت نتائج التطبيقات الإحصائية على المتغيرات المتماثلة والتحاليل العنقودية والتي استخدمت لاستخلاص التغيرات في مجاميع الدياتومات التي تم تعريفها وجود ست مجاميع من الدياتومات بناء على  ماعكسته متغيرات ببيئية محددة وبالذات متغير الملوحة. 
</p>
</trans-abstract>




<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
<title>Keywords</title>
<kwd>diatoms</kwd>
<x>, </x>
<kwd>multivariate analysis</kwd>
<x>, </x>
<kwd>streams</kwd>
<x>, </x>
<kwd>Socotra</kwd>
<x>, </x>
<kwd>Yemen</kwd></kwd-group> 
</article-meta>  
</front> 
<body>
<sec>
<title>Introduction</title>
<p>Streams are among the most threatened habitat types in the recent times. Awareness
of the deleterious effects of human pressures on streams has resulted in a long history
of monitoring using many biological indicators&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b1 b2 b3">[1&#x2013;3]</xref> A
number of studies have evaluated the effects of different stressors on stream
assemblages and many assessment systems have been developed including one or
more taxonomic groups. Diatoms are the most common and diverse group of algae
in many rivers and streams, and thus are important components of these
ecosystems&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b4">[4]</xref>. They are considered more suitable for biological
monitoring than many other organisms because of their seeming ubiquity,
short generation time, sensitivity to changes in nutrient levels, and diverse
assemblages&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b5">[5]</xref>. Moreover, diatoms are often used to monitor the
environmental changes in rivers and streams because of their range of response to
ionic content and composition. Their use in monitoring would be enhanced
significantly if species responses to the concentration of major ions in fresh waters
were better quantified&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b6">[6]</xref>.</p>
<p>In North America, Europe, Australia and Africa, benthic diatoms are frequently used to
assess the integrity of stream ecosystems&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b7 b8 b9 b10 b11 b12">[7&#x2013;12]</xref>.
Moreover, several studies have addressed the tolerances and preferences of diatoms along
a number of environmental gradients such as salinity, pH, trophy, saprobity and current
preference&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b13 b14 b15 b16">[13&#x2013;16]</xref>. Benthic diatoms are often used for
assessing nutrient enrichment&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b17 b16 b18 b19">[17,16,18,19]</xref>,
salinity&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b20">[20]</xref> and acidity&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b21 b22 b23">[21&#x2013;23]</xref>. They
also give a quick response to environmental changes&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b24 b25
b26 b27 b28 b29 b30 b31 b32 b33 b34">[24&#x2013;34]</xref>. In addition, they are now
increasingly used to examine changes to river systems&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b35
b36">[35,36]</xref>.</p>
<p>The present study focuses on distribution of diatoms in some streams from Socotra
Island at north-western of Indian Ocean. This island is considered one of the most
fascinating places on earth. It has very rich and diverse animals and plants, which are
found nowhere else on the earth. Many fauna and flora groups in the island remain to
be discovered. Socotra Island has drawn the attention of many researchers in recent
times&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b37 b38 b39 b40 b41 b42 b43 b44 b45 b46">[37&#x2013;46]</xref>. Their
studies mainly dealt with the biology, geochemistry, ecology, biodiversity, fisheries
and climate of the island. Relatively a few geological studies were carried out on
this island due to its extremely isolated location. However, no research on
diatom communities from Socotra Island has been carried out. In addition,
stream diatom autecology and distribution patterns within the island remain
unknown.</p>
<p>The main objective of this study was to obtain preliminary data about the
composition of the non-marine benthic diatom flora and their distribution in
different eleven streams in Socotra Island. This data can be used as the
biodiversity database that will be benefit for monitoring of the environmental
change.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Island description</title>
<p>The Socotra is the largest Yemeni island, located at the northwest Indian Ocean, between the latitudes <!--\xdollar\rm -->12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>30<!--\xdollar-->&#x2019;N and the
longitudes <!--\xdollar\rm -->          54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;E<!--\xdollar-->.
The island covers an area of about 3650&#x00A0;km<sup>2</sup> and it has about 500&#x00A0;km of coastal line
and is more than 130&#x00A0;km long from east to west, and 40&#x00A0;km wide from north
to south, with a spine of spectacular 1,500&#x00A0;m mountains along its length
(<xref rid="fig1">Fig.&#x00A0;1</xref>). To the north lies Oligocene-Miocene oceanic crust in water depth
reaching in excess of 2500m; whilst south of the island depth is generally less
than 250m over a distance of 70&#x00A0;km (Laughton, 1966 and Laughton et&#x00A0;al.
1970).
<fig  id="fig1">  
<label>Figure.&#x00A0;1</label> <!--,aboveskip=.8pc,abovecapskip=-.5pc,belowskip=-.5pc--><caption> 
<title> Map of Socotra Island, showing the location of sampling sites at 11
streams.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr1.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [b!]{fig1}--></p>
<p>The topographic elements in Socotra Island are: (1)&#x00A0;The range of Hajar Mountains,
which are located at the eastern part of the island along Arida Bay, and extending
north east to south west at a distance of about 25&#x00A0;km. (2)&#x00A0;The central plateau, which
occupies most of the island area. (3)&#x00A0;Coastal plains, which are situated in the north
and south of the island. (4)&#x00A0;The wadis (valleys): The plains are interspersed by
many valleys that run in the northern and southern parts of the island. The
wadis are represented by small streams. Many of the north-flowing wadis
terminate in small fresh or brackish lakes separated from the sea by spits an
admixture of fine grey soil. Tectonically, the Socotran Platform was affected
by the three phases of extensional tectonics associated with the episodic
movement of the Arabian, African and Indian Plates. These are 1: Late
Jurassic to Early Cretaceous extension associated with the breakup of eastern
Gondwanaland; 2: Late Jurassic to Early Cretaceous extension associated with
failed rifting along the Arabian Peninsula Najd Trend (several phases of
subsequent structuring, with characteristic translational aspects to the tectonic
movement, occurred in the Late Cretaceous/Early Palaeocene and Early
Oligocene); and&#x00A0;3: Oligi-Miocene extention related to the rifting of the Gulf of
Aden&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b47">[47]</xref>.</p>
<p>Climatically, the island lies in the northern tropics (<!--\xdollar\rm -->12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>30<!--\xdollar-->&#x2019;N&#x2013;<!--\xdollar\rm -->54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>E<!--\xdollar-->)
of the northwest Indian Ocean and is strongly influenced by the East
African&#x2013;Indian monsoon&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b37 b38 b45">[37,38,45]</xref>. In general,
the island is prevailed generally with relatively hot weather of which
the average daily temperature in Hajar Mountains ranges between 25&#x2013;<!--\xdollar\rm -->28<sup>&#x2218;</sup>C<!--\xdollar-->. In
June and July however, the temperatures reach its extreme and fall during January
and February. The average humidity ratio ranges between max&#x00A0;55% in August
and min&#x00A0;7% in January. The island is subjected to sharp southern westerly
winds during the summer months (June, July, August) with an average speed
between&#x00A0;13&#x2013;18&#x00A0;km/h, whose speed decreases gradually during September till
they end at the beginning of October. The average annual rainfall of the
island is 150&#x00A0;mm on the coastal plain to upwards of 500&#x00A0;mm in the interior
mountains&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b48">[48]</xref>, but this quantity fluctuates to a great extent from
one year to another.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Materials and methods</title>
<p>Over the course of this study, eleven streams draining into the north and north
eastern side of Socotra Island were sampled between&#x00A0;14 and&#x00A0;28 July, 2008
(<xref rid="fig1">Fig.&#x00A0;1</xref> and
<xref rid="tbl1">Table&#x00A0;1</xref>). The streams are small second or third order systems no more than
4&#x2013;10m wide and less than 1m deep. They were clear and shallow (max. depth
15&#x2013;70&#x00A0;cm) (<xref rid="fig2">Fig.&#x00A0;2</xref>). Stream water specific conductance was generally low (20&#x2013;250&#x00A0;<!--\xdollar\rm --><!--\TexTMu\removeaccent{-->&#x03BC;<!--}-->S&#x002F;cm<!--\xdollar-->), with
higher values potentially representing close to the coast. The stream water pH was
alkaline (7.3&#x2013;8.4) with no clear altitudinal trend.
<table-wrap  id="tbl1">  
<label>Table&#x00A0;1</label>  
<caption> 
<title> The locations of the studied samples in Socotra Island.</title> 
</caption>
<table frame="hsides" rules="groups"> 
<colgroup>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/></colgroup>
<thead> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">Sample No. </td> 
<td align="left">Location                                    </td> 
<td align="left">Latitude &#x2018;N&#x2019;                                                                                                    </td> 
<td align="left">Longitude &#x2018;E&#x2019;                                                                                                   </td>
</tr></thead>
<tbody> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">1                        </td> 
<td align="left">Arer stream (fresh water)              </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;33<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;09<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;27<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;34<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">2                        </td> 
<td align="left">From the mouth of the Arer stream </td> 
<td align="left">                                                                          </td> 
<td align="left">                                                                          </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">3                        </td> 
<td align="left">Terbek area (stream)                    </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;34<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;53<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;23<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;44<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">4                        </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Shafa                                 </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;36<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;19<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;19<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;18<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">5                        </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Qariat Tawmer                    </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;38<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;48<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;13<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;19<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">6                        </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Qariat Tawmer                    </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;39<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;11<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;12<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;36<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">7                        </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Debni                                </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;38<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;52<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;08<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;32<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">8                        </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Delshieh                             </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;41<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;24<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;07<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;48<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">9                        </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Souq                                  </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;40<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;04<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;03<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;43<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">10                      </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Serhen                               </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;38<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;42<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;02<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;11<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">11                      </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Serhen                               </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;38<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;44<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;02<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;20<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">12                      </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Hadibo                               </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;38<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;51<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        54<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;01<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;39<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">13                      </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Noujahar                            </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;38<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;19<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        53<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;56<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;16<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">14                      </td> 
<td align="left">Wadi Serhen (Dexem)                   </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;29<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;41<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        53<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;59<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;29<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">15                      </td> 
<td align="left">Dhahadhhah (fresh water)             </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        12<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;30<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;40<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\xdollar\rm -->        53<sup>&#x2218;</sup>&#x00A0;27<!--^{-->&#x2032;<!--}-->&#x00A0;00<!--^{-->&#x2033;<!--}--><!--\xdollar--> </td>
</tr> 
</tbody> 
</table>
</table-wrap>
<!--\setFloat [pos=b]{tbl1}--></p>
<p>Diatoms were extracted from 20g of dry sediments of each sample. The
sample was first treated by 30% HCl with heating to boiling point in order
to remove any carbonate fraction. Each sample was rinsed by distilled
water several times to become neutral. The procedure was repeated with <!--\xdollar\rm -->H
<sub>2</sub>O
<sub>2</sub><!--\xdollar-->to eliminate the organic matter, and the sample was then rinsed and
decanted repeatedly in distilled water. The coarse particles were removed
by further decantation. Finally, one drop of the final suspension was
dried onto cover slips, then mounted onto slides using Canada Balsam<sup><!--\text{-->&#x00AE;<!--}--></sup>(<!--\xdollar\rm -->R.I=1.74<!--\xdollar-->) for
light microscopy investigations. 500&#x00A0;diatom valves were counted and identified in each
sample at 1000x magnification with Carl Zeiss microscope.</p>
<p>Nomenclature and identification of diatoms were made using&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b49
b50 b51 b52 b53 b54 b55 b56">[49&#x2013;56]</xref>. In the case of recently described or redefined
taxa, more recent literature was applied&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b57 b58 b59 b60 b61 b62
b63 b64 b65 b66 b67">[57&#x2013;67]</xref>. All identifications were to species level where possible
and the relative abundance values were calculated. The most dominant species that
have relative abundance over&#x00A0;5% of the total diatom valves in 15 examined samples
were analyzed using the multivariate statistical programs. One barren sample is
excluded from the analysis. Examination of community patterns within the dataset
was done primarily using detrended correspondence analysis (DCA). Cluster analysis
was carried out using Euclidean distance measure and the average clustering method
of the investigated sampling sites&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b68">[68]</xref> to distinguish the diatom
assemblages.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Diatom results</title>
<p>A total of&#x00A0;145 specific and infraspecific diatom taxa representing 44 genera were
observed in all examined streams. A list of all taxa encountered is presented
in
<xref rid="tbl2">Table&#x00A0;2</xref>. All of the recognized diatom flora are reported for the first time for the
island. The distribution pattern of the identified diatom communities varies
significantly between the studied sites and indicates changes in the floristic
composition. At least&#x00A0;45 genera and&#x00A0;142 species of pennate diatoms and at least three
genera with five species of centric diatoms were identified. The most dominant
diatom flora in the streams were cosmopolitan. The highest and lowest numbers of
species were reported at the site&#x00A0;14 (Wadi Serhen) and site&#x00A0;12 (Wadi Hadibo)
respectively. The species composition was very variable from stream to other. The
dominant species most commonly found in every stream were 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> and
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic>. In the Wadi Serhen and Wadi Shafa streams, the diatom flora
were most dominant than the others streams, and the species composition was
differed considerably.
<table-wrap  id="tbl2">  
<label>Table&#x00A0;2</label>  
<caption> 
<title> List of the identified diatoms in the studied streams sites. (A <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> abundant, C <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> common, F <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> frequent, R <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> rare, X <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> excellent, G <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> good, M <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> medium, and P <!--\xdollar\rm -->=<!--\xdollar--> poor)</title> 
</caption>
<table frame="hsides" rules="groups"> 
<colgroup>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/>   
<col align="left"/></colgroup>
<thead> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">Diatom flora </td> 
<td align="left">Sampling Sites                    </td> 
<td align="left">1  </td> 
<td align="left">2  </td> 
<td align="left">3  </td> 
<td align="left">4  </td> 
<td align="left">5  </td> 
<td align="left">6  </td> 
<td align="left">7  </td> 
<td align="left">8  </td> 
<td align="left">9  </td> 
<td align="left">10 </td> 
<td align="left">11 </td> 
<td align="left">12 </td> 
<td align="left">13 </td> 
<td align="left">14 </td> 
<td align="left">15 </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">                                  </td> 
<td align="left">Abundance                        </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">B  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">                                  </td> 
<td align="left">Preservation                       </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">P </td> 
<td align="left">G </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">G </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">G </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">P  </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">X  </td> 
<td align="left">M </td> 
<td align="left">G  </td>
</tr></thead>
<tbody> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Achnanthes brevipes intermedia</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Cleve.                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Achnanthidium exiguum</italic> (Grunow) Czarn.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Achnanthidium exilis</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Round &#x0026; Bukht.                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Achnanthidium lanceolatum</italic> Breb. ex K&#x00FC;tz.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Achnanthidium microcephalum K&#x00FC;tz</italic>.                            </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Achnanthidium minutissimum</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Czarn.                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora angusta</italic> Greg.                                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis</italic> (C.Agardh) K&#x00FC;tz.                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora commutata</italic> Grun. in Van Heurck.                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora cymbifera</italic> Greg.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora holsatica.</italic>                                          </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora montana</italic> Krasske.                                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora normanii Rabenh</italic>.                                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora ovalis (</italic>K&#x00FC;tz.) K&#x00FC;tz.                                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora sp.</italic>                                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Amphora veneta K&#x00FC;tz</italic>.                                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Anomoeoneis sphaerophora</italic> (Ehrenb.) Pfitz.                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Brachysira vitrea</italic> (Grun.) R. Ross in Hartley.                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Caloneis budensis</italic> (Grunow) Krammer.                         </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Campylodiscus bicostatus</italic> W. Smith in Roper.                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cocconeis disculoides</italic> Hust.                                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cocconeis placentula</italic> Ehrenb.                                  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cocconeis pseudomarginata</italic> Greg.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cocconeis scutellum</italic> Ehrenb.                                  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cocconeis speciosa</italic> Greg.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cocconeis</italic> sp.                                               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cocconeis thumensis</italic> A. Mayer.                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Craticula accomoda</italic> (Hust) Mann.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Craticula ambigua</italic> (Ehrenb.) D.G.Mann.                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Craticula cuspidata</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Mann.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Craticula halophila</italic> (Grun. ex Heurck) Mann.                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Craticula perrotettii</italic> Grun.                                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Ctenophora pulchella</italic> (Ralfs ex K&#x00FC;tz.) Williams &#x0026; Round.            </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\tabularBreak -->   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cyclotella meneghiniana</italic> K&#x00FC;tz.                                 </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cyclotella ocellata</italic> Pant.                                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cymbella affinis</italic> K&#x00FC;tz.                                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cymbella amphicephala</italic> Naegeli ex K&#x00FC;tz.                         </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cymbella ancyli</italic> Cleve.                                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cymbella aspera</italic> (Ehrenb.) H. Perag. in Pell.                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Cymbella cistula (</italic>Ehrenb.) Kirchner.                           </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Dimeregramma fulvum</italic> (Greg.) Ralfs in Pritch.                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Dimeregramma minor</italic> (Greg.) Ralfs in Pritch.                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Diplomenora cocconeiformis.</italic>                                  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Diploneis bombus (</italic>Ehrenb.) Ehrenb. ex Cleve.                   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Diploneis elliptica (</italic>K&#x00FC;tz.) Cleve.                               </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Diploneis littoralis</italic> (Donk.) Cleve.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Diploneis ovalis</italic> (Hilse) Cleve.                                 </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Diploneis smithii</italic> (Br&#x00E9;b.) Cleve.                                </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonema auerswaldii</italic> Rabenh.                               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonema caespitosum</italic> K&#x00FC;tz.                                 </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonema gracile</italic> Ehrenberg.                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonema mesianum</italic> (Cholnoky) Mann.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonema minutum</italic> (Hilse in Rabenhorst) Mann.                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonema silesiacum</italic> (Bleisch in Rabenh.) Mann.               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonemopsis aequalis</italic> (W.Sm.) Krammer.                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Encyonemopsis microcephala</italic> (Grunow) Krammer                 </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Eunotia minor</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz) Grunow in Van Heurck.                    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Eunotia pectinalis</italic> (O.F. Mull.) Rabenh.                         </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Geissleria decussis (&#x00D8;strup) Lange-Bert. &#x0026; Metzeltin in Lange-Bert.</italic>  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Geissleria paludosa</italic> (Hust.) Lange-Bert. &#x0026; Metzeltin in Lange-Bert.   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Gomphonema clevei</italic> Fricke in A. Schmidt.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Gomphonema gracile</italic> Ehrenb.                                 </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Gomphonema parvulum</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) K&#x00FC;tz.                            </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Gomphonema parvulum exilissimum</italic> Grun. in V.Heurck.           </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R <!--\tabularBreak --> </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Gyrosigma acuminatum</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Rabenh.                         </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Gyrosigma diminutum</italic> (Grun. in Cleve &#x0026; Grun.) Cleve.             </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Gyrosigma hippocampus (</italic>Ehrenb.) Hassall.                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Hannaea arcus</italic> (Ehrenb.) Patr. in Patr. &#x0026; Reimer.                 </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Hantzschia amphioxys</italic> (Ehrenb.) Grun.                         </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Hantzschia virgata (</italic>Roper) Grun.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Hantzschia virgata gracilis</italic> Hust.                               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Hippodonta capitata</italic> (Ehrenb.) Lange-Bert., Metzeltin &#x0026; Witkowski.   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Hippodonta costulata (Grunow)</italic> Lange-Bert., Metzeltin &#x0026; Witkowski.  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Hippodonta hungarica</italic> (Grunow) Lange-Bert., Metzeltin &#x0026; Witkowski. </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Kobayasia subtilissima</italic> (Cleve) Lange-Bert.                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Lyrella lyra</italic> (Ehrenb.) Karayeva                               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Mastogloia braunii Grun</italic>.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Mastogloia dansei</italic> (Thwait.) Thwaites &#x0026; W. Smith.                </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Mastogloia elliptica</italic> (Ag.) Cleve ex A. Schmidt.                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Mastogloia smithii</italic> Thwaites ex W. Smith.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Mastogloia subafrimata.</italic>                                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Mastogloia</italic> sp.                                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula angusta Grun</italic>.                                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula aquaedurae</italic> Lange-Bertalot.                           </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula arabica Grun</italic>. ex A. Schmidt.                          </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula atomus</italic> (Kutz.) Grun.                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula capitoradiata</italic> Germain.                               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula cari Ehrenb</italic>.                                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula cincta</italic> (Ehrenb.) Ralfs in Pritch.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula clementis</italic> Grun.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula cruciculoides Brockm</italic>.                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula cryptocephala Kutz</italic>.                                  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula cryptotenella</italic> Lange-Bertalot.                          </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula digito-radiata</italic> (Greg.) Ralfs in Pritch.                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula florinae</italic> Moller.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\tabularBreak -->   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula globulifera</italic> Hustedt.                                  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula inflexa (</italic>Greg.) Ralfs in Pritch.                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula longa</italic> (Greg.) Ralfs in Pritch.                          </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula minuscula</italic> Grun. in Van Heurck.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula notha</italic> Wallace.                                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula phyllepta</italic> Kutz.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula radiosa</italic> Kutz.                                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula rhynchocephala</italic> Kutzing.                              </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula rostellata</italic> Kutz.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula</italic> sp.                                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula tenelloides Hust</italic>.                                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Navicula veneta Kutz</italic>.                                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia amphibia</italic> Grun.                                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia fonticola</italic> Grun. in Van Heurck.                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Grun.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia lanceolata</italic> W. Smith.                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia obtusa</italic> W. Smith.                                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia palea</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) W. Smith.                               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia perminuta</italic> (Grun.) M. Perag.                         </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia scalaris</italic> (Ehrenb.) W. Smith.                          </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia sigma</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) W. Smith.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia sigmoidea</italic> (Nitzsch) W. Smith.                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Nitzschia valdecostata.</italic>                                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Odontella aurita</italic> (Lyngb.) Ag.,                                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Pinnularia gibba (</italic>Ehrenb.) Ehrenb.                            </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Placoneis gastrum</italic> (Ehrenb.) Meresch.                          </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Plagiogramma staurophorum</italic> (Greg.) Heiberg.                    </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Planothidium delicatulum</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Round &#x0026; Bukht.                  </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Planothidium haukianum</italic> (Grun.) Round &#x0026; Burkht.                </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Pleurosigma angulatum</italic> (Quek.) W. Smith.                      </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Pleurosigma strigosum</italic> W. Smith.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Pleurosira laevis</italic> (Ehrenb.) Compere.                           </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left"><!--\tabularBreak -->   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Rhopalodia musculus</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) O. M&#x00FC;ll.                            </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Sellaphora bacillum</italic> (Ehrenb.) D.G.Mann.                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Sellaphora pupula</italic> (K&#x00FC;tz.) Mereschkowsky.                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Stauroneis phoenicenteron</italic> (Nitzsch) Ehrenb.                     </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Staurosirella pinnata</italic> (Ehrenb.) Williams &#x0026; Round.                 </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Stenopterobia delicatissima</italic> (Lewis) M. Perag.                    </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Synedra acus</italic> K&#x00FC;tzing.                                        </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Synedra longissima</italic> W. Smith.                                 </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Synedra nana</italic> Meister.                                       </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">C </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Synedra tabulata</italic> (Ag.) K&#x00FC;tz.                                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> (Nitzsch) Ehrenb.                                </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">F </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">A </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">C  </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Tropidoneis lepidoptera</italic> (Greg.) Cleve.                          </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Tryblionella acuminata</italic> W. Smith                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Tryblionella apiculata</italic> Greg.                                   </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Tryblionella granulata</italic> (Grun.) Mann.                           </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">A  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Tryblionella levidensis</italic> W. Smith.                              </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td colspan="2"  align="left">
<italic>Tryblionella punctata</italic> W. Smith.                               </td> 
<td align="left">    </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">F  </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">R  </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td> 
<td align="left">   </td>
</tr> 
<tr valign="top"> 
<td align="left">                                  </td>
</tr> 
</tbody> 
</table>
</table-wrap>
<!--\setFloat [pos=t]{tbl2}--><fig  id="fig2">  
<label>Figure.&#x00A0;2</label> <!--,aboveskip=.8pc,abovecapskip=-.5pc,belowskip=-.5pc--><caption> 
<title> The studied streams in Socotra Island: (a) Terbek stream, S.3, (b)
Wadi Qariat Tawmer close to the sea, S.5, (c) Wadi Qariat Tawmer, S.no.6, (d) Wadi
Delshieh, S.8 (e) Wadi Serhen, S.10, (f) Wadi Serhen, S.11, (g) Wadi Hadibo2, S.12,
(h) Wadi Noujahar, S.13, (i) Wadi Serhen (Dexem) stream, S.14, (j) Dhahadhhah
Stream, S.15.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr2.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [b!]{fig2}--></p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Diatom composition</title>
<p>While many species were found in the streams from all sites, relative abundances
indicate differences in diatom assemblages. In Arer stream at the eastern part of the
island, two samples were collected (sites&#x00A0;1 and&#x00A0;2). Low numbers of diatom taxa were
recorded with moderately preservation. Site&#x00A0;1 from the downstream region comprised
only 10 species, where the strongly dominant species was 
<italic>Pleurosira laevis</italic>, which has
maxima abundance 71% of the total assemblage. The association composed of
frequently to sporadic occurrence of 
<italic>Diploneis bombus, Diploneis elliptica, Diploneis
smithii, Eunotia minor, Gomphonema gracile, Hantzschia virgata, Mastogloia dansei,
Navicula rhynchocephala, Stenopterobia delicatissima</italic> and 
<italic>Synedra ulna.</italic> Site&#x00A0;2 from
the mouth of the Arer stream, close to the coast and&#x00A0;19 diatom species were
recognized. 
<italic>Mastogloia braunii</italic> has a maximum abundance, accounted for 44% of the
total assemblage, while 
<italic>Pleurosira laevis</italic> which is abundant at the site&#x00A0;1, it is
decreased in its relative abundance to&#x00A0;6.2% to become frequently distributed
in site&#x00A0;2. The diatom association is distinguished by common to frequent
occurrence of 
<italic>Mastogloia dansei</italic>, 
<italic>Mastogloia elliptica</italic>, 
<italic>Diploneis smithii, Nitzschia
amphibia</italic>, 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic>, 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic>, and sporadic distribution of
<italic>Amphora commutate, Diploneis littoralis, Gomphonema gracile, Mastogloia
smithii Navicula cincta, Craticula accomoda, Diploneis bombus</italic> and 
<italic>Eunotia
minor</italic>.</p>
<p>Terbek stream (site&#x00A0;3) north of the previous sites&#x00A0;1 and&#x00A0;2 at the eastern part of the
island. Low numbers of moderately preserved diatom species were recorded and
included only 22&#x00A0;taxa. The most dominant species was 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> has a relative
abundance&#x00A0;40% of the total community. The association contained the common
occurrence of 
<italic>Encyonema silesiacum</italic> (12%), 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic> (19%), 
<italic>Nitzschia
amphibia</italic> (10%), 
<italic>Nitzschia perminuta</italic> (8%) and 
<italic>Synedra longissima</italic> in combined with
frequently to rare distribution of 
<italic>Amphora veneta, Encyonema caespitosum,
Encyonema mesianum, Encyonema minutum, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Navicula
cryptocephala, Navicula tenelloides, Nitzschia valdecostata, Pinnularia gibba, Synedra
acus</italic>, and 
<italic>Synedra nana</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Shafa stream (site&#x00A0;4) close to the north eastern part of the island. A total of&#x00A0;54
well preserved diatom species were recognized. The most dominant species were
<italic>Tryblionella granulate</italic> (36%), 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic> (25%) and 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> (22%).
The association composed commonly of 
<italic>Nitzschia amphibia</italic> (11%) and 
<italic>Synedra nana</italic>
in-combined with frequently to sporadic occurrence of many taxa such as 
<italic>Amphora
veneta, Encyonema silesiacum, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Kobayasia
subtilissima, Gomphonema gracile, Gomphonema parvulum, Navicula cryptocephala,
Navicula cincta, Navicula rhynchocephala</italic>, 
<italic>Navicula tenelloides</italic> and 
<italic>Synedra
tabulate</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Qariat Tawmer stream, two samples were collected (sites&#x00A0;5 and&#x00A0;6), northeast of
the island. Site&#x00A0;5 was located in the middle part of wadi Qariat Tawmer, while site&#x00A0;6
was situated close to the island coast, where the stream water was relatively mixed
with sea water. Diatom assemblage characteristic site&#x00A0;5 was low diversity and
represented only by moderately preserved 22&#x00A0;diatom species. 
<italic>Staurosirella pinnata</italic> has
maximum abundance reaches about&#x00A0;40% of the total assemblage, and associated
with common occurrence of 
<italic>Cocconeis placentula</italic> that accounted for&#x00A0;25%.
The association is represented by frequently to rare abundance of 
<italic>Amphora
coffeaeformis, Amphora Montana, Campylodiscus bicostatus, Dimeregramma fulvum,
Dimeregramma minor, Diploneis bombus, Geissleria decussis, Lyrella lyra,
Navicula arabica, Navicula minuscula</italic>, 
<italic>Navicula rhynchocephala, Planothidium
haukianum, Planothidium delicatulum, Achnanthidium lanceolatum</italic>, and
<italic>Odontella aurita</italic>. However, site&#x00A0;6 is also represented by low diatom diversity
included moderately preserved&#x00A0;19 diatom species. The predominance taxon was
<italic>Tryblionella granulate</italic> which has accounted for&#x00A0;34% of the total assemblage, and
associated with common abundance of 
<italic>Cocconeis placentula</italic>&#x00A0;(18%). The diatom
association was characterized by frequently abundance of 
<italic>Achnanthes brevipes</italic>
var.
<italic>intermedia</italic>, 
<italic>Amphora angusta, Amphora coffeaeformis</italic>, 
<italic>Cocconeis disculoides,
Cocconeis scutellum, Diploneis smithii, Gyrosigma acuminatum, Gyrosigma
diminutum, Navicula cryptocephala, Nitzschia lanceolata, Plagiogramma
staurophorum, Planothidium haukianum, Synedra ulna</italic> and 
<italic>Tryblionella
punctata</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Debni stream (site&#x00A0;7) is a branch of Wadi Delshieh north of Socotra Island. The
diatom assemblage encountered from this stream contained only well preserved 31
diatom species. The Debni stream is distinguished from others studied streams by
abundance of 
<italic>Nitzschia</italic> species. 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic> was the dominant taxon, has
relative frequency of about&#x00A0;47% of the total assemblage, followed by abundance of
<italic>Nitzschia amphibia</italic>&#x00A0;(30%) and 
<italic>Nitzschia perminuta</italic> (12%). The diatom association
was characterized by frequently distribution of 
<italic>Navicula notha</italic>, 
<italic>Kobayasia
subtilissima, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Gomphonema gracile, Gomphonema
parvulum, Navicula cryptocephala, Navicula cryptotenella, Navicula rhynchocephala</italic>,
<italic>Nitzschia scalaris, Amphora Montana, Anomoeoneis sphaerophora, Aneumastus
tuscula, Brachysira vitrea, Caloneis budensis, Diploneis elliptica, Diploneis smithii,
Hantzschia virgata gracilis, Mastogloia braunii, Mastogloia elliptica, Mastogloia
smithii, Nitzschia scalaris</italic> and 
<italic>Synedra acus, Synedra longissima, Synedra
ulna</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Delshieh stream (site&#x00A0;8) is originated from Hafegy mountain and located in the
northern part of the island. The studied site is distinguished by diatom assemblage
differs from the other streams by predominance of 
<italic>Navicula</italic> species. The
recognized community contained well preserved&#x00A0;39 different diatom taxa.
The most dominant was 
<italic>Navicula cryptocephala</italic>, which is accounted for&#x00A0;49%
of the total assemblage and followed by common occurrence of 
<italic>Navicula
cincta</italic>&#x00A0;(27%), 
<italic>Navicula cryptotenella</italic> and 
<italic>Navicula rhynchocephala</italic>. The association
contained frequently to sporadic occurrence of 
<italic>Anomoeoneis sphaerophora,
Cocconeis placentula, Cyclotella meneghiniana, Cyclotella ocellata, Cymbella
affinis</italic>, 
<italic>Cymbella cistula, Diploneis ovalis, Diploneis smithii, Encyonema
silesiacum</italic>, 
<italic>Gomphonema gracile, Gomphonema parvulum, Hantzschia virgata,
Kobayasia subtilissima, Mastogloia elliptica</italic>, 
<italic>Mastogloia smithii, Navicula
cruciculoides</italic>, 
<italic>Navicula minuscula, Navicula radiosa, Nitzschia amphibia, Nitzschia
fonticola, Nitzschia frustulum, Nitzschia obtusa, Nitzschia palea</italic> and 
<italic>Synedra
ulna</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Souq stream (site&#x00A0;9) is located at the north of the island and it originates from
Deneqhen mountain. The diatom assemblage is included well preserved 23&#x00A0;diatom
species. 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> has a maximum abundance reaches to 35% of the total
assemblage. 
<italic>Encyonema caespitosum</italic> and 
<italic>Encyonema silesiacum</italic> were recorded
commonly (14% and 12.8&#x00A0;respectively) followed by common occurrence of 
<italic>Navicula
cryptotenella, Navicula rhynchocephala, Encyonema mesianum, Gomphonema gracile</italic>
and 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic>. The diatom association comprised also frequently to rare
distribution of 
<italic>Achnanthidium exiguum, Nitzschia amphibia, Amphora holsatica,
Amphora montana, Amphora normanii, Anomoeoneis sphaerophora, Caloneis
budensis, Cyclotella meneghiniana, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Hantzschia
virgata, Kobayasia subtilissima, Navicula cari, Navicula cincta</italic> and 
<italic>Nitzschia
palea</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Serhen stream was originated from Dahzafeq mountain and pour its water into
the Arabian Sea at the north. The investigated samples were collected from three
sites;&#x00A0;10 and&#x00A0;11 are located at the north of the island, where the wadi was dominant by
palm trees. Site&#x00A0;14 was situated in the middle part of the island behind Dexem
plateau where the freshwater from the rains made up many lakes with depth of
about&#x00A0;4 metres. The diatom flora in the sites&#x00A0;10 and&#x00A0;11 are similar in diversity and
abundance and the preservation was well. A total of&#x00A0;35 and&#x00A0;33 diatom species were
recognized from these sites respectively. The most dominant diatom species was
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> which accounted for&#x00A0;41% (site&#x00A0;10) to&#x00A0;39% (site&#x00A0;11) of the total
assemblage. The diatom association in both sites was relatively similar but
differs only in the relative abundance of species. The diatom community was
contained frequently to sporadic occurrence of 
<italic>Anomoeoneis sphaerophora,
Cyclotella meneghiniana, Encyonema mesianum, Encyonemopsis microcephala,
Gomphonema gracile, Mastogloia elliptica, Navicula cryptocephala, Navicula
cryptotenella, Navicula rhynchocephala, Nitzschia frustulum</italic> and 
<italic>Nitzschia
palea</italic>.</p>
<p>The diatom assemblage of site 14 is relatively similar to that recorded in both sites&#x00A0;10
and&#x00A0;11, but differs in the relative abundance of the dominant species with prominent
other taxa not recognized in these sites. A total of well preserved 60&#x00A0;diatom
species are recorded. 
<italic>Tryblionella acuminate</italic> is the most dominant taxon and
accounted for&#x00A0;28% of the total assemblage. The 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> is less abundant
and attains about&#x00A0;22% of the community. The diatom association contained
frequently common occurrence of 
<italic>Amphora angusta, Amphora montana,
Anomoeoneis sphaerophora, Gomphonema parvulum, Gyrosigma acuminatum,
Hippodonta costulata, Mastogloia braunii, Navicula cryptocephala, Navicula
minuscula, Navicula rhynchocephala, Nitzschia amphibia</italic> and 
<italic>Tryblionella
apiculata</italic>. However, the rare abundance diatoms are 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis,
Amphora commutate, Amphora normanii, Amphora ovalis, Craticula cuspidate,
Cymbella affinis, Encyonema caespitosum</italic>, 
<italic>Encyonema mesianum, Encyonema
minutum, Encyonema silesiacum, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Geissleria
decussis, Gomphonema gracile, Gyrosigma hippocampus, Hantzschia amphioxys,
Kobayasia subtilissima, Mastogloia dansei, Mastogloia elliptica, Navicula
atomus, Navicula cincta, Navicula clementis, Navicula cryptotenella, Navicula
notha, Navicula phyllepta, Navicula rostellata, Navicula tenelloides, Nitzschia
frustulum, Nitzschia lanceolata, Nitzschia obtuse, Nitzschia palea, Nitzschia
scalaris</italic>, 
<italic>Pleurosigma angulatum, Pleurosigma strigosum</italic> and 
<italic>Rhopalodia
musculus</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Hadibo stream (site&#x00A0;12) is originated from Ferdhakhah mountain and the wadi
is dominated by palm trees. The stream discharges its water into the Indian Ocean at
the north. The diversity of the diatoms is very low and moderately preserved, where
the assemblage contained only eight species. 
<italic>Campylodiscus bicostatus</italic> and 
<italic>Amphora
coffeaeformis</italic> are the most dominant flora and accounted for&#x00A0;36% and&#x00A0;30% of the total
community. The association comprised common occurrence of 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> (14%),
<italic>Nitzschia sigma</italic>&#x00A0;(10%) in-combined with frequently distribution of 
<italic>Anomoeoneis
sphaerophora, Cocconeis placentula, Gyrosigma diminutum</italic> and 
<italic>Nitzschia
obtuse</italic>.</p>
<p>Wadi Noujahar stream (site&#x00A0;13) discharge into the Arabian Sea at the north. The
sample is obtained close to the coast where the freshwater mixed with sea water. No
diatoms were recorded at this site.</p>
<p>Dhahadhhah stream (site&#x00A0;15) is small, shallow freshwater and originated
from granitic mountains that located in the western part of the island. The
diatom assemblage is characterised by well-preserved 44 diatom species.
<italic>Encyonemopsis microcephala</italic> has maximum abundance accounted for&#x00A0;39%
of the total assemblage and followed by 
<italic>Mastogloia braunii</italic> of about&#x00A0;23%.
The diatom association is contained commonly occurrence of 
<italic>Mastogloia
dansei, Mastogloia elliptica, Diploneis smithii, Synedra ulna</italic> in combined
frequently distribution of 
<italic>Amphora commutata, Amphora cymbifera, Brachysira
vitrea, Cymbella ancyli, Gomphonema gracile, Mastogloia smithii, Nitzschia
amphibia, Nitzschia frustulum, Synedra longissima</italic> and sporadic occurrence of
<italic>Achnanthidium microcephalum, Achnanthidium minutissimum, Amphora
coffeaeformis, Amphora veneta, Anomoeoneis sphaerophora, Craticula cuspidate,
Craticula halophila, Cymbella aspera, Diploneis elliptica, Encyonema gracile,
Encyonema mesianum, Gomphonema parvulum, Navicula cryptocephala, Navicula
cryptotenella, Navicula tenelloides, Navicula veneta, Nitzschia palea</italic> and 
<italic>Staurosirella
pinnata</italic>.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Discussion</title>
<p>Application of multivariate statistical techniques using detrended correspondence and
cluster analyses on the most common diatom taxa in the examined&#x00A0;15 sampling sites
led to recognition of six different diatom assemblages, with variation in dominant
species and composition (<xref rid="fig3 fig4 fig5">Figs.&#x00A0;3&#x2013;5</xref>). The data set includes species that were abundant but
present in one and relatively fewer samples, such as 
<italic>Pleurosira laevis, Staurosirella
pinnata, Cocconeis placentula, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Navicula cryptocephala,
Synedra ulna, Tryblionella acuminata, Tryblionella granulata</italic>. As well as less
abundant species that were nevertheless common, such as 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis,
Amphora commutate, Amphora montana, Amphora veneta, Anomoeoneis
sphaerophora, Campylodiscus bicostatus, Cocconeis placentula, Dimeregramma
fulvum, Dimeregramma minor, Diploneis bombus, Diploneis elliptica, Diploneis
smithii, Encyonema caespitosum, Encyonema mesianum, Encyonema silesiacum,
Gomphonema gracile, Gomphonema parvulum, Gyrosigma diminutum, Kobayasia
subtilissima, Mastogloia braunii, Mastogloia dansei, Mastogloia elliptica, Mastogloia
smithii, Navicula cincta, Navicula cryptotenella, Navicula rhynchocephala, Navicula
tenelloides, Nitzschia amphibia, Nitzschia frustulum, Nitzschia obtuse, Nitzschia
perminuta, Planothidium haukianum, Tryblionella acuminata</italic> and 
<italic>Tryblionella
punctata</italic>.
<fig  id="fig3">  
<label>Figure.&#x00A0;3</label> <!--,aboveskip=.8pc,abovecapskip=-.5pc,belowskip=-.5pc--><caption> 
<title> Cluster analysis of the studied samples based on the relative
abundance of the most common diatom taxa.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr3.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [b!]{fig3}--><fig  id="fig4">  
<label>Figure.&#x00A0;4</label> <!--,aboveskip=.8pc,abovecapskip=-.5pc,belowskip=-.5pc--><caption> 
<title> Detrended correspondence analysis (DCA) differentiated the studied
sampling sites into six groups.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr4.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [bh!]{fig4}--><fig  id="fig5">  
<label>Figure.&#x00A0;5</label> <!--,aboveskip=.8pc,abovecapskip=-.5pc,belowskip=-.5pc--><caption> 
<title> Detrended correspondence analysis (DCA) based on dominant
diatom species.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr5.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [bh!]{fig5}--></p>
<p>The results indicate that the distribution pattern of diatoms in the studied sediments
streams may influenced by some environmental variables, such as salinity,
substrate type and water depth. The recognized diatom assemblages were largely
dominated by non-planktonic forms; this attributed to the collection of samples
from water depth not exceed than one meter, since the decreasing depth is
often correlated with an increased proportion of the benthic and epiphytic
habitats.</p>
<p><bold>Assemblage I</bold> was recorded only from site&#x00A0;8 at Delshieh stream. This assemblage is
characterized by predominance of 
<italic>Navicula cryptocephala</italic> (49%) and 
<italic>Navicula cincta</italic>
(27%). These two species are considered to be benthic forms, alkaliphilous with
pH values&#x00A0;7.5&#x2013;8.0 and distributed in eutrophic, fresh to slightly brackish
water&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b69 b70">[69,70]</xref>. In addition, the diatoms association contains
many taxa characteristic of the ecological preferences of fresh to slightly brackish
water, such as 
<italic>Navicula cryptotenella, Navicula rhynchocephala, Cocconeis placentula,
Diploneis ovalis, Diploneis smithii, Encyonema silesiacum</italic>,
<italic> Gomphonema gracile,
Gomphonema parvulum, Hantzschia virgata, Kobayasia subtilissima, Mastogloia
elliptica</italic>, 
<italic>Mastogloia smithii, Navicula cruciculoides</italic>, 
<italic>Nitzschia amphibia, Nitzschia
frustulum, Nitzschia obtusa, Nitzschia palea</italic> and 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic>. The diatom
assemblage denotes that the Delshieh stream water was freshwater origin with
slightly elevated salinity during the arid climatic condition with increasing
temperature that lead to some water evaporation.</p>
<p><bold>Assemblage II</bold> is characteristic of Wadi Shafa stream (site&#x00A0;4), Wadi Qariat
Tawmer stream (site&#x00A0;6) and Wadi Debni stream (site&#x00A0;7). The predominance
presence of 
<italic>Tryblionella granulata</italic> and the frequent occurrence of 
<italic>Navicula
cryptocephala</italic> in the samples of Shafa stream (site&#x00A0;4) and Qariat Tawmer stream
(site&#x00A0;6) is resulted from the similarity in environmental conditions in these two
sites.</p>
<p>The occurrence of the temperate coastal species 
<italic>Tryblionella granulata</italic> in site&#x00A0;6 from
Wadi Qariat Tawmer reflects high brackish water conditions and the elevated
salinity levels in alkaline, eutrophic shallow water. The sample is collected
from area where the marine water mixed with freshwater of the stream.
This may the reason to abundance of 
<italic>Tryblionella granulata</italic>. However, in
site&#x00A0;4, this species is considered to be of allochthonous origin, and it has been
transported into the Shafa stream by marine currents, particularly during the
season of higher sea level, since the species is a marine diatom, found in
coastal lagoons and estuaries&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b85">[85]</xref>, very rare in continental
environments&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b89 b80">[89,80]</xref>. Moreover, its occurrence may be due
to the ability of tides to transport cells in a diurnal basis, with high spring tides or
storm surges being especially proficient at mixing species from different
environments&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b90 b91">[90,91]</xref>.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the similarity between sites&#x00A0;4 and&#x00A0;7 is represented in the
abundance of freshwater flora including, 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic> (25% and 47%
respectively), and 
<italic>Nitzschia amphibia</italic> (11% and 30% respectively). 
<italic>Nitzschia
frustulum</italic> is a freshwater, alkaliphilous form, distributed also in meso- to
eutrophic, slightly brackish water&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b71 b72">[71,72]</xref> tolerant
to pollution and also mesohalobic species&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b73">[73]</xref>. 
<italic>Nitzschia
amphibia</italic> is a benthic, alkalibiontic, with pH value over&#x00A0;8, lives in eutrophic
freshwater&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b69 b71">[69,71]</xref>. Beside the dominant taxa many other
freshwater forms are recorded infrequently within the assemblage such as 
<italic>Kobayasia
subtilissima, Encyonemopsis microcephala, Gomphonema gracile, Gomphonema
parvulum, Navicula cryptocephala, Navicula rhynchocephala</italic>, 
<italic>Nitzschia scalaris</italic>, and
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic>.</p>
<p>Although the cluster and DCA analyses appeared a similarity between the three
sites&#x00A0;4,&#x00A0;6 and&#x00A0;7, based on the dominant diatoms, nevertheless each site is characterized
by diatom association differs relatively from the other sites. Site 6 is characterized by
diatom association contained frequently of 
<italic>Achnanthes brevipes</italic> var. 
<italic>intermedia</italic>,
<italic>Amphora angusta, Amphora coffeaeformis</italic>, 
<italic>Cocconeis disculoides, Cocconeis
scutellum, Diploneis smithii, Gyrosigma acuminatum, Gyrosigma diminutum,
Nitzschia lanceolata, Plagiogramma staurophorum, Planothidium haukianum</italic> and
<italic>Tryblionella punctata</italic>. These taxa characteristic brackish water and denote to
elevated salinity. This community not recorded in both sites of Wadi Shafa stream&#x00A0;(4)
and Wadi Debni stream&#x00A0;(7). However, site&#x00A0;7 of Wadi Debni stream comprises other
diatom association represented by frequently occurrence of mixed slightly brackish to
freshwater forms such as 
<italic>Amphora Montana, Anomoeoneis sphaerophora,
Aneumastus tuscula, Mastogloia braunii, Mastogloia elliptica</italic> and 
<italic>Navicula
notha</italic>. Site&#x00A0;4 of wadi Shafa stream is contained diatom association differs
from the previous sites and represented by frequently occurrence of many
freshwater forms such as 
<italic>Amphora veneta, Cymbella affinis, Cymbella aspera,
Diploneis elliptica, Encyonema mesianum, Encyonema silesiacum, Navicula
cincta, Navicula tenelloides, Pinnularia gibba</italic> and 
<italic>Synedra nana</italic>. The diatom
communities in both sites&#x00A0;4 and&#x00A0;7 elucidate freshwater to slightly brackish water
environment.</p>
<p><bold>Assemblage III</bold> was recognized from Wadi Qariat Tawmer stream (site&#x00A0;5) and
Wadi Hadibo stream (site&#x00A0;12). Although similarities in diatom community
composition can be seen between these streams, the order and dominance of
species differed between them, with the most obvious examples being the
abundance of 
<italic>Staurosirella pinnata</italic> (39%), associated with common occurrence of
<italic>Cocconeis placentula</italic>&#x00A0;(22%) in sediment streams of Wadi Qariat Tawmer (site&#x00A0;5) in
comparison with sediment stream of Wadi Hadibo (site&#x00A0;12) and the abundance of
<italic>Campylodiscus bicostatus</italic>&#x00A0;(32%) co-dominant with 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis</italic>&#x00A0;(29%) in
sediments stream at site&#x00A0;12 in comparison with sediment streams at site&#x00A0;5.
Differences in the dominant diatoms between the streams&#x00A0;5 and&#x00A0;12 may be related
to a number of environmental factors, such as variations in the substrate
type.</p>
<p>However, similarity between these sites (5 and 12) is attributed to a great abundance
of epiphytic and benthic pleiroeuryhaline and mesohalobous diatom species with
considerable numbers of some coastal marine forms. Of these taxa are 
<italic>Amphora
coffeaeformis</italic>, 
<italic>Campylodiscus bicostatus, Cocconeis placentula, Dimeregramma
fulvum, Dimeregramma minor, Diploneis bombus, Lyrella lyra, Navicula arabica,
Navicula</italic> and 
<italic>Odontella aurita</italic>.</p>
<p><italic>Staurosirella pinnata</italic> and 
<italic>Cocconeis placentula</italic> reached maximum abundance
throughout Wadi Qariat Tawmer stream (site&#x00A0;5). 
<italic>Staurosirella pinnata</italic> is
eurytopic form, common in the littoral part of eutrophic waters, epiphytic,
beta-mesosaprobic and preference for oligotrophic water with relatively low
conductivity, it lives in fresh and brackish water as plankton or epiphytic,
alkaliphilous, with pH value 7.5&#x2013;8.0&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b69 b74 b55
b56">[69,74,55,56]</xref>. 
<italic>Cocconeis placentula</italic> is a widespread eurytopic species, epiphytic on
aquatic plants and other objects; more commonly found in circumneutral to
alkaline waters with pH values 7.5&#x2013;8.0, and recorded in waters up to 17&#x2013;20&#x00A0;g/l
salinity&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b75 b76 b69">[75,76,69]</xref>. These two species reflects warm,
shallow, eutrophic slightly brackish water conditions&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b77">[77]</xref>.
They denote the development of macrophytes in quite parts of the eutrophic
water&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b78">[78]</xref>.</p>
<p><italic>Campylodiscus bicostatus</italic> and 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis</italic> have maximum abundance
with common appearance of 
<italic>Synedra ulna</italic> and 
<italic>Nitzschia sigma</italic> in Wadi
Hadibo stream (site&#x00A0;12). 
<italic>Campylodiscus bicostatus</italic> is a benthic, mesohalobous
species&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b79">[79]</xref>. 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis</italic> is a benthic, polyhalobous,
pleioeuryhaline&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b79">[79]</xref>. It can lives as epipelic, epiphytic or
aerophilous in stagnant or running water of medium to high conductivity, it is
eurythermal&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b70">[70]</xref>. 
<italic>Nitzschia sigma</italic> is an eutrophic mesohalobous
species, commonly found in water with pH value 7.5&#x2013;8.3&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b80
b81">[80,81]</xref>. Generally, the common occurrence of epiphytic, mesohalobous taxa
combined with some coastal marine forms suggests elevated salinity and high
brackish water conditions with development of macrophytes characteristic the Wadi
Qariat Tawmer stream (site&#x00A0;5) and Wadi Hadibo stream (site&#x00A0;12). As well as
high abundance of eutrophic taxa reflects high nutrients matter at these
localities.</p>
<p><bold>Assemblage IV</bold> was observed in sediments from the mouth of the Arer stream
(site&#x00A0;2) and from Dhahadhhah stream (site&#x00A0;15). The good similarity between these
sites is due to the predominance of slightly brackish water benthic species combined
with many freshwater forms. 
<italic>Mastogloia braunii</italic> has maximum abundance in the two
sites reached&#x00A0;44% and&#x00A0;32% respectively. This species is a benthic form, common in
brackish water, estuarine &#x201C;mesohalobous&#x201D;, alkaliphilous&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b82 b83
b84">[82&#x2013;84]</xref>. The diatom association of both sites contained also common to frequent
occurrence of others mesohalobous forms such as 
<italic>Mastogloia dansei</italic>, 
<italic>Mastogloia
elliptica</italic>, 
<italic>Mastogloia smithii, Pleurosira laevis</italic>, 
<italic>Diploneis smithii</italic> and 
<italic>Nitzschia
amphibia</italic>. The freshwater diatom taxa are distributed infrequently in the sediments
stream of site&#x00A0;2, while they are commonly found in the sediments stream of
site&#x00A0;15, where 
<italic>Encyonemopsis microcephala</italic> is dominant. But in overall, the
recognized diatom assemblage reflects shallow, warm, mesotrophic, slightly
brackish water conditions at both sites from the mouth of the Arer stream and
Dhahadhhah stream, with an influence of freshwater from these streams, which
may be loaded with some high metal concentrations and moderate nutrients
matter.</p>
<p><bold>Assemblage V</bold> was covering many sites from different three wadis, including Terbek
stream (site&#x00A0;3), Wadi Souq stream (site&#x00A0;9) and Wadi Serhen stream (sites&#x00A0;10, 11, 14).
The very good similarity between these sites is attributed to predominance of
freshwater diatom taxa, in particular the tychoplanktonic 
<italic>Synedra</italic> ulna, which has
maxima abundance ranges between&#x00A0;30 to&#x00A0;40% of the total assemblage. This species is
considered as a freshwater form, common in meso- to eutrophic lakes and streams,
epiphytic and benthic, with pH optimum is about&#x00A0;7.8&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b51 b85
b72">[51,85,72]</xref>. The diatom species association is represented in these sites by
fairly common freshwater benthic forms such as 
<italic>Navicula cincta, Navicula
cryptocephala, Navicula rhynchocephala</italic>, 
<italic>Cymbella affinis, Cymbella amphicephala,
Encyonema caespitosum, Encyonema minutum, Encyonema silesiacum,
Encyonemopsis microcephala, Gomphonema gracile, Nitzschia frustulum</italic> and
<italic>Nitzschia perminuta</italic>. The brackish water and marine forms are distributed sparsely.
The recognized freshwater taxa are similar to those reported from several freshwater
environments in the world. The high abundance of benthic, mesotrophic
and eutrophic freshwater diatom taxa, denote the high nutrients levels and
the effects of freshwater influx and perhaps some sewage inflow to these
studied wadis. Moreover, the occurrence of many eutrophic and mesosaprobic
taxa may records the effect of human population growth with increasing
sewering.</p>
<p>However, site 14 of Wadi Serhen stream is distinguished by abundance of 
<italic>Tryblionella
acuminate</italic> (30%), which is not recorded in other sites. This species is recorded as a
brackish water form, polyhalobous, meioeuryhaline, it usually inhabits the
marine littoral zone, in waters with medium to high conductivities, pH and
alkalinities&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b79 b70 b84">[79,70,84]</xref>. Its occurrence abundantly
with some other brackish water forms such as 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis, Nitzschia
amphibia, Nitzschia obtuse, Nitzschia scalaris</italic> and 
<italic>Tryblionella apiculata</italic>
indicative to slightly elevated salinity at this site in the middle part of the
island.</p>
<p><bold>Assemblage VI</bold> is characteristic of site 1, from Arer stream in the eastern part of
Socotra Island. This site is distinguished from other sites of different streams by low
diatom diversity and the dominant species is 
<italic>Pleurosira laevis</italic>, which has maximum
abundance, reaches to 71% of the total assemblage. This species is a mesohalobous
and characteristic of high brackish water conditions&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b79 b86">[79,86]</xref>.
<italic>Diploneis smithii</italic> and 
<italic>D. bombus</italic> are relatively common (9%), and distinguish also
high brackish water conditions and found in both brackish and coastal marine
environments&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b80 b53 b81">[80,53,81]</xref> The diatom association is
represented by frequently occurrence of 
<italic>Diploneis elliptica, Gomphonema
gracile, Hantzschia virgata, Mastogloia dansei, Navicula rhynchocephala,
Stenopterobia delicatissima</italic> and 
<italic>Synedra ulna. Hantzschia virgata</italic> is regarded
as being mesohalobous and prefers clean sandy shores to estuarine mud
by&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b87 b88">[87,88]</xref>. The predominance of these taxa suggests high
brackish water conditions with elevated salinity in the Arer stream. This may
attributed to intrusion of the sea water into the Arer stream during period of rising
sea level.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Conclusions</title>
<p>A detailed study on diatom assemblages separated from&#x00A0;15 samples collected from the
surface sediments at different streams in Socotra Island revealed 145 diatom
species belonging to&#x00A0;44 genera, which were the first record in the island.
Multivariate statistical technique including Detrended correspondence and the
cluster analyses were used to summarize changes in the diatom assemblages
present in the examined streams. The results indicated six major diatom
assemblages with variation in dominant species. Each assemblage reflects
distinctive environmental conditions based on salinity preference of the recognized
and dominant flora. It can be noted from the composition of the diatom
assemblages found in the studied streams that most of the identified diatom flora
prefer warm, eutrophic, slightly alkaline, freshwater and brackish conditions.
The majority of the diatom species identified from streams sediments are
common in eutrophic rivers. Most species identified are epilithic, but some are
epipelic, and others are epiphytic species. A few species, such as 
<italic>Cyclotella
meneghiniana</italic>, are typical of the plankton of larger rivers and lakes. The
predominance of non-planktonic taxa compared to planktonic forms may
be attributed to the shallowness of the environments with high nutrients
levels.</p>
<p>The distribution pattern of recorded diatom flora and species composition showed
differences the relative abundances between the studied streams. A number of taxa
showed spatial variability, increasing in relative abundances in eastern streams. These
include 
<italic>Pleurosira laevis, Mastogloia braunii, Synedra ulna, Tryblionella granulata</italic>
and 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum</italic>. While in the north-eastern streams 
<italic>Staurosirella
pinnata</italic>, 
<italic>Cocconeis placentula</italic> and 
<italic>Tryblionella</italic> 
<italic>granulata</italic> have maximum
relative abundance. In the northern streams, the most dominant species
are 
<italic>Nitzschia frustulum, Nitzschia amphibia</italic>, 
<italic>Nitzschia perminuta, Navicula
cryptocephala</italic>, 
<italic>Navicula cincta</italic>, 
<italic>Navicula cryptotenella</italic>, 
<italic>Navicula rhynchocephala</italic>,
<italic>Encyonema caespitosum</italic>, 
<italic>Encyonema silesiacum, Synedra ulna, Tryblionella
acuminata, Campylodiscus bicostatus</italic> and 
<italic>Amphora coffeaeformis</italic>. However,
<italic>Encyonemopsis microcephala</italic> was observed to be abundant in the western
stream.</p></sec></body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<title>References</title>
<ref id="b1">
<label>[1]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>De Pauw
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Hawkes
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1993</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Biological monitoring of river water quality</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Proceedings of the &#x2018;Freshwater
Europe Symposium on River Water Quality Monitoring and Control&#x2019;</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor">
<string-name>
<surname>Walley
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>W.J.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Judd
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Published by Aston University</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Aston, UK</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>87</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>111</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b2">
<label>[2]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Rosenberg
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Resh
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>V.H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1993</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Introduction to freshwater biomonitoring and benthic macroinvertebrates</article-title>
<x>.
</x>
<source>Freshwater Biomonitoring and Benthic Macroinvertebrates</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Rosenberg
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.M.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name>
<string-name>
<surname>Resh
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>V.H.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Chapman and Hall</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>9</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b3">
<label>[3]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Knoben,  R.A.,   Roos,  E.C., &#x0026;   Van Oirschot,  M.C.M..  1995,
Biological Assessment Methods for Watercourses. UN/ECE Task Force on
Monitoring and Assessment. Volume 3. RIZA report no. 95.066. Lelystad.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b4">
<label>[4]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Round
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1981</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>The ecology of algae</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>Cambridge University Press</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Cambridge</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>629</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b5">
<label>[5]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>De La Rey
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>P.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Taylor
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.C.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Laas
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Van Rensburg
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Vosloo
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2004</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Determining the possible application value of diatoms as indicators of
general water quality: A comparison with SASS 5</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Water SA</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>30</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>325</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>332</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b6">
<label>[6]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Potapova
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Charles
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.F.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2003</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Distribution of benthic diatoms in U.S. rivers in relation to conductivity and
ionic composition</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Freshwater Biology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>48</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1311</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>1328</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b7">
<label>[7]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Gasse
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Juggins
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Khelifa
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.B.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1995</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatom-based transfer functions for inferring past hydrochemical
characteristics of African lakes</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Palaeogeogr. Palaeoclimat. Palaeoecol.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>117</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>31</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>54</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b8">
<label>[8]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Lowe
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.L.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Pan
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>Y.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1996</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Benthic algal communities as biological monitors</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Algal Ecology: Freshwater
Benthic Ecosystems</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Stevenson
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.J.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Bothwell
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.L.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Lowe
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.L.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>,
</x>
<publisher-name>Academic Press</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>San Diego</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>705</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>739</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b9">
<label>[9]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Kelly
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.G.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Cazaubon
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Coring
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Dell&#x2018;uomo
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Ector
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Goldsmith
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Guasch
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>H&#x00FC;rlimann
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Jarlman
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Kawecka
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Kwandrans
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Laugaste
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Lindstr&#x00F8;m
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.-A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Leitao
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Marvan
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>P.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Padis&#x00E1;k
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Pipp
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Prygiel
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname><!--\unskip \break -->Rott
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Sabater
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Van dam
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Vizinet
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1998</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Recommendations for the routine sampling of diatoms for water quality
assessments in Europe</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Jour. Appl. Phycol.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>10</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>215</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>224</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b10">
<label>[10]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Chessman
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Growns
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>I.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Currey
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Plunkett-Cole
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Predicting diatom communities at the genus level for the rapid biological
assessment of rivers</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Freshwater Biology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>41</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>317</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>331</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b11">
<label>[11]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Prygiel
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Coste
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Ector
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Projets d&#x2019;intercalibration europ&#x00E9;ens et mise en place d&#x2019;une
charte de qualit&#x00E9; diatom&#x00E9;es pour l&#x2019;IBD (et l&#x2019;IPS) in Compte-rendu du <!--\xdollar\rm -->17<sup>&#x2218;</sup><!--\xdollar-->colloque de l&#x2019;Association des Diatomistes de langue Fran&#x00E7;aise, Luxembourg, 8-11
September 1998</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Cryptogamie-algologie</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>20</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>2</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>139</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>142</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b12">
<label>[12]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Stevenson
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Pan
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>Y.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Assessing environmental conditions in rivers and streams with diatoms</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>The
Diatoms: Applications for the Environmental and Earth Sciences</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor">
<string-name>
<surname>Stoermer
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.F.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Smol
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.P.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Cambridge University Press</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Cambridge</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>11</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>40</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b13">
<label>[13]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Denys,  L..  1991a, A check-list of the diatoms in the Holocene deposits of the
Western Belgian coastal plain with a survey of their apparent ecological
requirements. I. Introduction, ecological code and complete list. Minist&#x00E9;re des Affaires
Economiques &#x2013; Service G&#x00E9;ologique de Belgique.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b14">
<label>[14]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Denys,  L..  1991b, A check-list of the diatoms in the Holocene deposits of the
Western Belgian coastal plain with a survey of their apparent ecological
requirements. II. Centrales. Minist&#x00E9;re des Affaires Economiques - Service G&#x00E9;ologique de
Belgique.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b15">
<label>[15]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>van Dam
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Mertens
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Sinkeldam
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1994</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>A coded checklist and ecological indicator values of freshwater diatoms from
the Netherlands</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Netherlands Journal of Aquatic Ecology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>28</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>1</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>117</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>133</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b16">
<label>[16]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Rott,  E.,   Hofmann,  G.,   Pall,  K.,   Pfister,  P., &#x0026;   Pipp,  E..
1997, Indikationslisten f&#x00FC;r Aufwuchsalgen. Teil 1: Saprobielle Indikation.
Bundesministerium f&#x00FC;r Land- und Forstwirtschaft, Wien, 73 pp.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b17">
<label>[17]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Kelly
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.G.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Penny
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>C.J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Whitton
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1995</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Comparative performance of benthic diatom indices used to asess river water
quality</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Hydrobiologia</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>302</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>179</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>188</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b18">
<label>[18]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">   Rott,  E.,   Pfister,  P.,   Van Dam,  H.,   Pipp,  E.,   Pall,  K.,   Binder,  N., &#x0026;   Ortler,  K..
1999, Indikationslisten f&#x00FC;r Aufwuchsalgen. Teil 2: Trophieindikation sowie
geochemische Pra<!--\"{--> <!--}\removeaccent{-->&#x00A8;<!--}-->ferenz, taxonomische und toxikologische Anmerkungen.
Bundesministerium f&#x00FC;r Land- und Forstwirtschaft, Wien, 248&#x00A0;pp.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b19">
<label>[19]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Coring
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Situation and developments of algal (diatom)-based techniques for monitoring
rivers in Germany</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Use of Algae for Monitoring Rivers III</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Prigiel
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name>
<string-name>
<surname>Whitton
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.A.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Bukowska
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Agence de l&#x2019;Eau Artois-Picardie</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>France</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>122</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>127</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b20">
<label>[20]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Ziemann
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Bestimmung des Halobienindex</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Biologische Gewa<!--\"{--> <!--}\removeaccent{-->&#x00A8;<!--}-->sseruntersuchung</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor">
<string-name>
<surname>T&#x00FC;mpling
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>W.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Friedrich
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>G.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<series>Methoden der Biologischen Gew&#x00E4;sseruntersuchung</series>
<x>, </x>
<volume>2</volume>
<x>,
</x>
<fpage>310</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>313</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b21">
<label>[21]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Coring
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1993</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Zum Indikationswert bentischer Diatomeengesellschaften in basenarmen
Flie&#x00DF;gewa<!--\"{--><!--}\removeaccent{-->&#x00A8;<!--}-->ssern</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>Verlag Shaker</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Aachen</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b22">
<label>[22]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Battarbee
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.W.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Flower
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Juggins
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Patrick
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.T.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Stevenson
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.C.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1997</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>The relationship between diatoms and surface water quality in the Hoylandet
area of Nord-Trondelag, Norway</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Hydrobiologia</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>348</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>69</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>80</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b23">
<label>[23]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>van Dam
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1997</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Partial recovery of moorland pools from acidification: indications by
chemistry and diatoms</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Netherlands Journal of Aquatic Ecology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>30</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>203</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>218</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b24">
<label>[24]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Schoeman
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.R.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Haworth
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.Y.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1986</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatom as indicator of pollution</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Proceedings of the Eighth International
Diatom Symposium 1984</source>
<x>. </x>
<x> Ed. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Ricard
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Koeltz Scientific Books</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Koenigstein</publisher-loc>
<x>.
</x>
<fpage>757</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>766</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b25">
<label>[25]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Prygiel
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1991</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Use of benthic diatoms in surveillance of the Artois-Picardie basin
hydrobiological quality</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Use of algae for monitoring rivers</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Whitton
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.A.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name>
<string-name>
<surname>Rott
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Friedrich
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>G.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Institut f&#x00FC;r Botanik, Univ. Innsbruck</publisher-name>
<fpage>89</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>96</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b26">
<label>[26]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Round
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1991</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatoms in river water-monitoring studies</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Journal of Applied Phycology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>3</volume>
<x>,
</x>
<fpage>129</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>145</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b27">
<label>[27]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Round
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1993</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>A Review and Methods for the Use of Epilithic Diatoms for Detecting and
Monitoring Changes in River Water Quality</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>HMSO Publisher</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>63</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b28">
<label>[28]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Kelly
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.G.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Whitton
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1995</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>The Trophic Diatom Index: a new index for monitoring eutrophication in
rivers</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Jour. Appl. Phycol.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>7</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>433</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>444</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b29">
<label>[29]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Descy
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.P.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Ector
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Use of diatoms for monitoring rivers in Belgium and Luxemburg</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Use of algae
for monitoring rivers III</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Prygiel
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Whitton
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.A.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Bukowska
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Agence
de l&#x2019;Eau Artois-Picardie</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Douai</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>128</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>137</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b30">
<label>[30]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Whitton
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Rott
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1995</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Use of algae for monitoring rivers II</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Proc. II International Symposium</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor">
<string-name>
<surname>Whitton
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.A.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Rott
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Innsbruck</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Austria</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>17</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>19</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<!--\pagebreak { \advance \baselineskip.18pt--><ref id="b31">
<label>[31]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Kelly
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.G.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2002</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Role of benthic diatoms in the implementation of the Urban Wastewater
Treatment Directive in the River Wear, North-East England</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Jour. Appl. Phycol.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>14</volume>
<x>,
</x>
<fpage>9</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>18</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b32">
<label>[32]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Lobo,  E.A.,   Callegaro,  V.L., &#x0026;   Bender,  P..  2002, Utiliza&#x00E7;&#x00E3;o de
algas diatom&#x00E1;ceas epil&#x00ED;ticas como indicadoras da qualidade da &#x00E1;gua em rios e arroios da
Regi&#x00E3;o Hidrogr&#x00E1;fica do Gua&#x00ED;ba, RS, Brasil. Santa Cruz do Sul: 
<italic>EDUNISC</italic>. 127p.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b33">
<label>[33]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Lobo
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Callegaro
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>V.L.M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Hermany
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>G.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>G&#x00F3;mez
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Ector
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2004</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Review of the use of microalgae in South America for monitoring rivers, with
special reference to diatoms</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Vie et Milieu-Life and Environment</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>54</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>105</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>114</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b34">
<label>[34]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Salomoni,  S.E..  2004, Diatom&#x00E1;ceas Epil&#x00ED;ticas indicadoras da Qualidade de &#x00E1;gua
na Bacia do Rio Gravata&#x00ED;, Rio Grande do Sul, Brasil. 230&#x00A0;pp. (Tese de Doutorado) &#x2013;
PPGERN- UFSCar, S&#x00E3;o Carlos, S&#x00E3;o Paulo.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b35">
<label>[35]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Thoms
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.C.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Ogden
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.W.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Reid
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Establishing the condition of lowland floodplain rivers: a palaeo-ecological
approach</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Freshwater Biology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>41</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>407</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>423</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b36">
<label>[36]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Reid
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Fluin
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Ogden
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Tibby
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Kershaw
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>P.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2002</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Long-term perspectives on human impacts on floodplain-river ecosystems,
Murray-Darling Basin, Australia. Verhandlungen der Internationalen Vereinigung f&#x00FC;r
Theoretische und Angewandte</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Limnologie</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>28</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>2</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>710</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>716</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b37">
<label>[37]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hastenrath
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1994</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Climate Dynamics of the Tropics</source>
<x>. </x>
<volume>vol.&#x00A0;8</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Boston</publisher-loc>
<x>.
</x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b38">
<label>[38]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Webster
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>P.J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Magana
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>V.O.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Palmer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>T.N.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Shukla
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Tomas
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Yanai
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Yasunari
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>T.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1998</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Monsoons: processes, predictability, and the prospects for prediction</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Jour.
Geophys. Res.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>103</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>14451</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>14510</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b39">
<label>[39]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Krupp,  F., &#x0026;   Hariri,  K.I..  1999, Conservation and sustainable use of
biodiversity of Socotra Archipelago. Marine Habitat, Biodiversity and Fisheries
Surveys and Management. Report of Phase I: Frankfurt: UNOPS YEM/96/G32,
Contract No. C-972248: 1&#x2013;212.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b40">
<label>[40]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Krupp,  F., &#x0026;   Klaus,  R..  1999, Contributions to a zoning plan for coastal
and marine areas of Socotra. In Marine Habitat and Biodiversity and Fisheries
Surveys and Management. Progress Report of Phase II. UNOPS YEM/96/G32
Contract No. C-972248.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b41">
<label>[41]</label>
<mixed-citation publication-type="other">    Simo,  E.S.N., &#x0026;   Jones,  D.A..  2000, Intertidal and coastal lagoons
ecology survey of Socotra. In 
<italic>Report of Phase II. Marine Habitat and Biodiveristy
and Fishereis Surveys and Management</italic>. UNOPS YEM/96/G32 Contract No.
C-972248.</mixed-citation> </ref>
<ref id="b42">
<label>[42]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Stramma
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Brandt
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>P.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Schott
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Quadfasel
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Fischer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2002</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Winter and summer monsoon water mass, heat and freshwater transport
changes in the Arabian Sea near 81N</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Deep-Sea Research II</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>49</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1173</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>1195</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b43">
<label>[43]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Klaus
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Jones
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Turner
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Sim&#x00F6;es
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Vousden
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2003</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Integrated Marine and coastal management: a strategy for the conservation
and sustainable use of marine biological resources in the Socotra Archipelago, Yemen</article-title>
<x>.
</x>
<source>Journal of Arid Environments</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>54</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>71</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>80</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b44">
<label>[44]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Combes
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.J.D.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Caulet
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.P.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Tribovillard
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2005</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Monitoring the variations of the Socotra upwelling system during the last 250
kyr: A biogenic and geochemical approach</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimat. Palaeoecol</source>
<x>,
</x>
<volume>223</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>3&#x2013;4</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>243</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>259</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b45">
<label>[45]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Fleitmann
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Burns
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Mangini
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Mudelsee
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Kramers
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Villa
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>I.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Neff
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>U.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Al-Subbary
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Buettner
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Hippler
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Matter
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2004</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Holocene ITCZ and Indian monsoon dynamics recorded in stalagmites from
Oman and Yemen (Socotra)</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Quat. Sci. Rev</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>26</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>170</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>188</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b46">
<label>[46]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Shakun
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.D.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Burns
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Fleitmann
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Kramers
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Matter
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Al-Subary
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2007</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>A high-resolution, absolute-dated deglacial speleothem record of Indian
Ocean climate from Socotra Island, Yemen</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Earth and Planetary Science Letters</source>
<x>,
</x>
<volume>259</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>442</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>456</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b47">
<label>[47]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Birse
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.C.R.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Bott
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>W.F.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Morrison
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Samuel
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1997</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>The Mesozoic and Early Tertiary tectonic evolution of the Socotra area,
eastern Gulf of Aden, Yemen</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Marine and Petroleum Geology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>14</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>6</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>675</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>684</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b48">
<label>[48]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Miller
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.G.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Cope
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>T.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1996</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Flora of the Arabian Peninsula and Socotra</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>Edinburgh University Press</publisher-name>
<x>,
</x>
<publisher-loc>Edinburgh</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b49">
<label>[49]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hustedt
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1930</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Die Kieselalgen</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Rabenhorst, Kryptogamen-Flora von Deutschland, &#x00D6;sterreich
und der Schweiz</source>
<x>. </x>
<series>Teal</series>
<x>, </x>
<volume>1</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Acad. Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Leipzig</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>920</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b50">
<label>[50]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hustedt
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1955</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Marine littoral diatoms of Beaufort, North Carolina</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Duke Univ. Mar. Stn.
Bull.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>6</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>67</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b51">
<label>[51]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hustedt
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1959</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Die Kieselalgen</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Rabenhorst, Kryptogamen-Flora von Deutschland, &#x00D6;sterreich
und der Schweiz</source>
<x>. </x>
<series>Teal</series>
<x>, </x>
<volume>3</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Acad. Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Leipzig</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>845</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b52">
<label>[52]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hustedt
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1961-1966</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Die Kieselalgen Deutschlands, &#x00D6;sterreichs und der Schweiz, 3. Teil</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>L.
Rabenhorst&#x2019;s Kryptogamen-Flora, Band 7/3</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>Koeltz Scientific Books</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Champaign</publisher-loc>
<x>.
</x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>816</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b53">
<label>[53]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1986</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Bacillariophyceae.1 Teil: Naviculaceae</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>S&#x00FC;sswasserflora von Mitteleuropa
(begruendet von A. Pascher)</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Ettl
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Gerloff
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Heynig
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name>
<string-name>
<surname>Mollenhauer
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<volume>2(1)</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Gustav Fischer Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Stuttgart</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>876</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b54">
<label>[54]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1988</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Bacillariophyceae.1: Bacillariaceae, Epithemiaceae, Surirellaceae</article-title>
<x>.
</x>
<source>S&#x00FC;sswasserflora von Mitteleuropa (begruendet von A. Pascher)</source>
<x>. </x>
<x>Eds. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Ettl
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name>
<string-name>
<surname>Gerloff
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>J.</given-names>
<x>, </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname>Heynig
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names>
<x> &#x0026; </x></string-name> 
<string-name>
<surname><!--\unskip \break -->Mollenhauer
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<volume>2</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Gustav Fischer Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Stuttgart</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>596</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b55">
<label>[55]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1991a</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Bacillariophyceae, 3. Teil: Centrales, Fragilariaceae, Eunotiaceae</source>
<x>.
</x>
<series>S&#x00FC;&#x00DF;wasserflora von Mitteleuropa</series>
<x>, </x>
<volume>2/3</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Gustav Fischer Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Stuttgart &#x0026; Jena</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>576</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b56">
<label>[56]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1991b</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Bacillariophyceae, 4. Teil: Achnanthaceae, Kritische Erganzungen zu
Navicula (Lineolate) und Gomphonema</source>
<x>. </x>
<series>S&#x00FC;&#x00DF;wasserflora von Mitteleuropa</series>
<x>, </x>
<volume>2/4</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Gustav
Fischer Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Stuttgart &#x0026; Jena</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>437</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b57">
<label>[57]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Round
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.E.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Crawford
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.M.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Mann
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.G.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1990</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>The diatoms. Biology and morphology of the genera</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>Cambridge University
Press</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Cambridge</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>747</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b58">
<label>[58]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Bukhtiyarova
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Round
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1996a</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Revision of the genus 
<italic>Achnanthes</italic> sensu lato section 
<italic>Marginulatae</italic> Bukht.
sect. nov. of 
<italic>Achnanthidium</italic> K&#x00FC;tz</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatom Research</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>11</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>30</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b59">
<label>[59]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Bukhtiyarova
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>L.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Round
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1996b</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Four new genera based on 
<italic>Achnanthes</italic> (<italic>Achnanthidium</italic>) together with a
re-definition of 
<italic>Achnanthidium</italic></article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatom Research</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>11</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>345</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>361</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<!--} \pagebreak --><ref id="b60">
<label>[60]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Metzeltin
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1996</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Indicators of Oligotrophy. Ecology-Diversity-Taxonomy</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Iconographia
Diatomologica</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>2</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>390</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b61">
<label>[61]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1997</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Die Cymbelloiden Diatomeen. Eine Monographie der Werltweit be Konnten
Taxa Teil 1. Algem eineis und 
<italic>Encyonema</italic> Part. 
<italic>Bibliotheca Diatomologica band</italic></article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>J.
Cramer, Stuttgart.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>36</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>382</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b62">
<label>[62]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Genkal
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.I.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1999</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatomeen aus Sibirien I. Inseln im Arktischen Ozean (Yugorsky - shar
Strait)</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Iconographia Diatomologica</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>6</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>292</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b63">
<label>[63]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Metzeltin
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>D.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2000</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatoms from the &#x2018;Island Continent&#x2019; Madagascar. Taxonomy-Biogeography-Diversity</article-title>
<x>.
</x>
<source>Iconographia Diatomologica</source>
<x>. </x>
<x> Ed. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<series>11</series>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Koeltz Scientific Books,
Gantner Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>K&#x00F6;nigstein</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>286</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b64">
<label>[64]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2001</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatoms of Europe</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatoms of the European Inland Waters and Comparable
Habitats</source>
<x>. </x>
<x> Ed. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<series>
<italic>Navicula</italic> sensu stricto. 10 genera Separated from
<italic>Navicula</italic> sensu lato. 
<italic>Frustulia</italic></series>
<x>, </x>
<volume>2</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Koeltz Scientific Books, Gantner Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>K&#x00F6;nigstein</publisher-loc>
<x>.
</x>
<fpage>526</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b65">
<label>[65]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2000</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatoms of Europe. Diatoms of the European Inland Waters and Comparable
Habitats</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>The Genus 
<italic>Pinularia</italic></source>
<x>. </x>
<x> Ed. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<volume>Volume 1</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Koeltz
Scientific Books, Gantner Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>K&#x00F6;nigstein</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>703</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b66">
<label>[66]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2002</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatoms of Europe</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatoms of the European Inland Waters and Comparable
Habitats</source>
<x>. </x>
<x> Ed. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<series>Cymbella</series>
<x>, </x>
<volume>3</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Koeltz Scientific Books, Gantner
Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>K&#x00F6;nigstein</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>584</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b67">
<label>[67]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Krammer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2003</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatoms of Europe. Diatoms of the European Inland Waters and Comparable
Habitats</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Cymbopleura, Delicata, Navicymbula, Gomphocymbellopsis, Afrocymbella</source>
<x>.
</x>
<x> Ed. </x>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"> 
<string-name>
<surname>Lange-Bertalot
<x xml:space="preserve"/> </surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name></person-group>
<x>, </x>
<volume>4</volume>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-name>Koeltz Scientific Books, Gantner Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>K&#x00F6;nigstein</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>530</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b68">
<label>[68]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Carney
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.J.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1982</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Algal dynamics and trophic interactions in the recent history of Frains Lake,
Michigan</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Ecology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>63</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1814</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>1826</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b69">
<label>[69]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Ehrlich
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1973</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Quaternary Diatoms of the Hula Basin (Northern Israel)</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Bulletin Geological
Survey Israel</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>58</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>39</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b70">
<label>[70]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Gasse
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1986</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>East African Diatoms. Taxonomy, ecological distribution</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Bibliotheca
Diatomologica</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>11</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>202</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b71">
<label>[71]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Lowe
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.L.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1974</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Environmental requirements and pollution tolerance of freshwater diatoms.
National Environmental Research Center</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency</publisher-name>
<x>,
</x>
<publisher-loc>Cincinnati, Ohio, U.S.A</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>333</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b72">
<label>[72]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Foged
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1993</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Some diatoms from Siberia, especially from Lake Baikal</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatom Research</source>
<x>,
</x>
<volume>8</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>2</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>231</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>279</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b73">
<label>[73]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Ehrlich
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Ortel
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1979</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>The Influence of salinity on the Benthic Diatoms Communities of the Lower
Jordan River</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Nova Hedwigia</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>64</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>325</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>336</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b74">
<label>[74]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Salden
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1978</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Beitr&#x00E4;ge Zur &#x00D6;kologie Der Diatomeen (Bacillanophyceae) des S&#x00FC;sswassers</article-title>
<x>.
</x>
<source>Naturhistorischer Verein, Bonn Dechiniana Beih</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>22</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>231</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b75">
<label>[75]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Simonsen
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1962</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Untersuchungen zur Systematik und Okologie der Bodendiatomeen der
westlichen Ostsee</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Internationale Revue der gesamten Hydrobiologie</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>1</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>144</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b76">
<label>[76]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Patrick
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Reimer
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>C.W.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1966</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>The diatoms of the United States exclusive of Alaska and Hawaii</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Monograph
Academy Natural Sciences Philadelphia</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>1</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>688</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b77">
<label>[77]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Zalat
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Servant Vildary
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2007</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Environmental change in Northern Egyptian Delta lakes during the
late Holocene, based on diatom analysis</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Jour. Paleolimnology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>37</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>273</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>299</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b78">
<label>[78]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Zalat
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2000</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Distribution and paleoecological significance of fossil diatom assemblages
from the Holocene sediments of Lake Manzala, Egypt</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatom Research</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>15</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>1</issue>
<x>),
</x>
<fpage>167</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>190</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b79">
<label>[79]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Pankow
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>H.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1976</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Algenflora der Ostsee</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>II. Plankton</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>Verlag Fischer</publisher-name>
<x>, </x>
<publisher-loc>Stuttgart</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>493</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b80">
<label>[80]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Foged
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1980</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatoms in Egypt</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Nova Hedwigia</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>33</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>629</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>707</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b81">
<label>[81]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Zalat
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2002</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Distribution and origin of diatoms in the bottom sediments of the
Suez canal lakes and adjacent areas, Egypt</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatom Research</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>17</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>1</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>243</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>266</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b82">
<label>[82]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Foged
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1970</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>The diatomaceous flora in a Postglacial Kieselgur deposit in Southwestern
Norway</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Nova Hedwigia, Beih</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>31</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>169</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>202</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b83">
<label>[83]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Baudrimont
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>R.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1974</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Recherches sur les diatom&#x00E9;es des eaux continentales de 1&#x2019;A1g&#x00E9;rie: &#x00E9;co1ogie
et pa1&#x00E9;o&#x00E9;cologie</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>M&#x00E9;m. Soc. Hist. Nat. Afr. du Nord</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>12</volume>
<x>, </x>
<comment>N.S. 1-249, 22 pls.</comment></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b84">
<label>[84]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Zalat
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2003</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Paleoecological and environmental history of Lake Mariut, Egypt, by means
of diatoms</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Diatom Research</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>18</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>1</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>161</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>184</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b85">
<label>[85]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Cholnoky
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>B.J.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1968</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Die &#x00D6;kologie der Diatomeen in Binnengew&#x00E4;ssern</source>
<x>. </x>
<publisher-name>Lehre. J. Cramer Verlag</publisher-name>
<x>,
</x>
<publisher-loc>Berlin</publisher-loc>
<x>. </x>
<fpage>699</fpage>
</element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b86">
<label>[86]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Zalat
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.A.</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Servant Vildary
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>S.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2005</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Distribution of diatom assemblages and their relationship to environmental
variables in the surface sediments of three northern Egyptian lakes</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Jour.
Paleolimnology</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>34</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>159</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>174</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b87">
<label>[87]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hustedt
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>F.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1957</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Die Diatomeenflora des Fluss-systems der Weser im Gebiet der Hansestadt
Bremen</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Abhandlungen Naturwissenschaftlichen Verein zu Bremen</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>34</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>181</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>440</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b88">
<label>[88]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hendey
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.I.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1964</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>An introductory account of the smaller algae of British coastal waters.
Bacillariophyceae (Diatoms)</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Fishery Investigations Series</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>4</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>5</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>317</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b89">
<label>[89]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Foged
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>N.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1977</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Freshwater diatoms in Ireland</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Bibliotheca Phycologica</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>34</volume>
<x>, </x>
<fpage>1</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>221.s</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b90">
<label>[90]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Hemphill-Haley
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>E.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1995</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Diatom evidence for earthquake-induced subsidence and tsunami 300 yr ago
in southern coastal Washington</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Geological Society America Bulletin</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>107</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>3</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>367</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>378</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b91">
<label>[91]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Zalat
<x xml:space="preserve"/></surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A.A.</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>1997</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Distribution of Holocene diatoms and silicoflagellates in bottom sediments of
the Lake Timsah, Suez Canal area, Egypt</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Egypt. Jour. Geol.</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>41</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>1</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>103</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>128</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
</ref-list>
</back></article>
