<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Atypon//DTD Atypon Systems Journal Archiving and Interchange NLM DTD v3.0.0 20090430//EN" "atypon-archivearticle3.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article">
<front>
<journal-meta> 
<journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">connect</journal-id> 
<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">connect</journal-id> 
<journal-title-group> 
<journal-title>QScience Connect</journal-title> 
</journal-title-group> 
<issn pub-type="ppub">2223-506X</issn> 
<publisher> 
<publisher-name>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals</publisher-name>
</publisher> 
</journal-meta> 
<article-meta> 
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">9</article-id> 
<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5339/connect.2012.9</article-id> 
<article-categories> 
<subj-group subj-group-type="heading"> 
<subject>Review article</subject> 
</subj-group> 
</article-categories> 
<title-group> 
<article-title>Qatar&#x2019;s economy: Past, present and future</article-title> 
</title-group> 
<contrib-group>   
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<string-name>
<given-names>Ibrahim</given-names>
<x> </x>                
<surname>Ibrahim</surname> </string-name> 
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>               
<x>, </x></contrib>   
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<string-name>               
<given-names>Frank</given-names>
<x> </x>                
<surname>Harrigan</surname>
</string-name> 
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>
<x><sup>,</sup></x> 
<xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c1"><sup>&#x204E;</sup></xref>              
<x>, </x></contrib> 
<aff id="aff1"><sup>1</sup>Economic Advisor to HH Emir of Qatar and Executive Member of
the Supreme Committee for Development Planning, Emiri Diwan, Doha,
Qatar</aff> 
<aff id="aff2"><sup>2</sup>Department of Economic Development, General Secretariat for Development
Planning, Doha, Qatar</aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes> 
<corresp id="c1"><sup>&#x204E;</sup>Email: fharrigan@gsdp.gov.qa</corresp> 
<fn id="FN1">
<label>Academic Editors: </label>
<p>Nimir Elbashir, Texas A&#x0026;M University at
Qatar, Doha, Qatar</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN2">
<p>Justin Dargin, Oxford University Centre for the Environment,
Oxford, UK</p></fn></author-notes> 
<pub-date pub-type="pub"> 
<day>6</day> 
<month>9</month> 
<year>2012</year> </pub-date> 
<issue content-type="issue-sequence">2012</issue>
<elocation-id>9</elocation-id> 
<history> 
<date date-type="received">
<day>1</day>
<month>6</month>
<year>2012</year></date> 
<date date-type="accepted">
<day>5</day>
<month>8</month>
<year>2012</year></date></history>
<permissions> 
<copyright-statement>&#x00A9;&#x00A0;2012 Ibrahim and Harrigan, licensee
Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals. This is an open access article distributed
under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License CC BY 3.0 which
permits unrestricted use, distribution and reproduction in any medium, provided the
original work is properly cited.</copyright-statement> 
<copyright-year>2012</copyright-year> 
<copyright-holder>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals</copyright-holder> </permissions>
<self-uri content-type="pdf" xlink:href="connect.2012.9.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>  
<abstract>
<title>Abstract</title>
<p>In this review, the story of Qatar&#x2019;s economic emergence is told chronologically, beginning with Qatar&#x2019;s independence and the discovery of the North Field gas reservoir in 1971 and ending with the steps that Qatar is now taking as it transitions towards a more diversified and innovative economy.</p></abstract>
 
</article-meta>  
</front> 
<body>
<sec>
<title>Introduction</title>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s economic ascent of recent years has few parallels. It was not preordained by
its bountiful carbon resources, nor did it occur merely by chance. Many
countries blessed by resources have failed to prosper and develop. In Qatar,
successful development of its hydrocarbon resources followed from visionary and
committed national leadership, robust and mutually rewarding relationships with
international partners, and vigorous execution. Geopolitics in the Arabian Gulf and
the shifting tides of energy demand in distant markets have also played a
role.</p>
<p>Perhaps, with hindsight, the basis for Qatar&#x2019;s success may seem self-evident, but, in
truth, success followed from decisions that entailed significant risks. The huge North
Field&#x2014;the world&#x2019;s largest non-associated gas reservoir&#x2014;was first discovered in 1971,
but it took 20 years before its potential was unlocked&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b1">[1]</xref>. Despite its
massive gas resources, Qatar&#x2019;s location and distance from major markets, faulty
assessments of technical feasibility and value, and funding challenges hampered
profitable exploitation.</p>
<p>In the first phase of the development of its North Field gas resources, which
got underway in the early 1990s, Qatar focused on meeting its domestic
needs. But given the vastness of the resource, Qatar was fully aware that
successful exploitation would require exports. Early plans to supply Gulf
Cooperation Council (GCC) neighbours through a pipeline grid did not
materialize.</p>
<p>For over a decade, Qatar worked hard to break through constraints that impeded
exports of liquefied natural gas (LNG). In 1997, Qatar&#x2019;s first shipment reached the
shores of Japan. Top leadership commitment and perseverance, the creation of vital
infrastructure, new openings for reliable gas supplies in the Far East, and successful
partnerships with international oil companies eventually enabled Qatar to sell its
LNG in bulk and at a profit in Japan (to Chubu Electric). Having overcome these
hurdles, Qatar never looked back. Over the next 15 years, it built a competitive LNG
value chain with a global reach. Qatar succeeded by scaling up, integrating
downstream and building a reputation as a reliable and flexible partner and
supplier.</p>
<p>In the late 1990s, and with an eye on expanding opportunities in the fuel transport
market, Qatar turned its attention to opportunities to convert lean gas into
clean-burning gas-to-liquid fuels (GTLs). Taking measured risks, at a time when oil
prices were low and GTL&#x2019;s commercial prospects were uncertain, Qatar
broke new ground with its joint venture partners. Construction on Oryx
GTL, the world&#x2019;s first commercial-scale GTL plant, began in 2003, and
production came on stream in 2007. Work on the US$ 23 billion Pearl GTL
plant, now the world&#x2019;s largest GTL facility, started in 2007 and swung into
production in 2011. Meanwhile, Qatar&#x2019;s oil sector, which had been largely
written off in the early 1980s&#x2014;as its fields aged and oil prices dipped&#x2014;found a
new lease of life. By the late 1990s, production sharing agreements with
international oil companies, and the application of horizontal drilling methods, had
yielded substantial increases in recoverable reserves and reversed declines in
production.</p>
<p>Outcomes speak for themselves. Qatar is now the largest exporter of LNG and GTLs
in the world, with a supply chain that spans the globe. Downstream, Qatar is
building new industries from scratch, such as polyethylene, which add value to its
low-cost feedstock. And though gas has now taken over the reins, oil continues to
make a significant contribution to exports and to fiscal revenues. Qatar is now
reliably serving global energy markets&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b2">[2]</xref>.</p>
<p>Large financial dividends have followed from Qatar&#x2019;s investments in oil and gas, and
its macroeconomic achievements have been impressive. Since 2000, Qatar has grown
faster than any other economy, and it now ranks among the top flight of countries in
terms of its income per capita. Growth in oil and gas revenues has afforded
higher living standards and rising consumer spending among Qataris. But a
significant portion of hydrocarbon income has been saved, and the debts
accumulated in the 1990s, as Qatar invested in its hydrocarbon&#x2019;s industry, have now
been largely amortized. Qatar&#x2019;s generous surpluses have funded a range of
investments. To meet the needs of a growing economy and larger population, Qatar
has spent prodigiously on expanding and upgrading economic and social
infrastructure.</p>
<p>Qatar has also used its resources to hedge against uncertainty and to build a legacy
for future generations. Understanding the risks of tying expenditure on essential
services to volatile oil revenues, Qatar established sizeable financial endowments early
on to provide continuity and predictability of funding for health and education
services. Realizing, too, that alternative forms of wealth creation would eventually
have to replace finite hydrocarbon resources, Qatar Foundation (QF) was created in
1994 to expand opportunities in education and scientific research, and to promote
community development. This was followed in 1998 by the establishment of
Education City, a-state-of-the-art campus and learning environment. Then, in 2005,
the Qatar Investment Authority (QIA) was formed as the primary vehicle for
state financial investment. Through the QIA, the state not only sought to
accumulate funds for the future, but also to diversify the asset classes in which it
invested.</p>
<p>Even during the early extractive phase of its development, Qatar had started to
venture beyond oil and gas. Qatar Airways, the national flag carrier, started from
modest beginnings in 1994, and was re-launched in 1997 under a new ownership
structure and management. The television news network, Al Jazeera, now a global
media player, first broadcast in Arabic in late 1996. In 2004, Qatar Science
Technology Park, a hub for technological innovation and commercialization was
opened. It acquired status as a free-zone in 2006. Soon recognizing that information
and communications technology would be integral to realizing a prosperous future,
ICT Qatar, a regulator and development agency for the industry, was created in
2004. The Qatar Financial Centre Authority, a platform to promote the
development of the financial services industry, was established by the government in
2005.</p>
<p>There were also important institutional advances during these years. The Permanent
Constitution, promulgated in 2004, defined the principles to guide the regulation of
the state and its institutions. From an economic perspective, it guaranteed rights to
private property and economic freedom and established the state&#x2019;s ownership of the
country&#x2019;s hydrocarbon resources.</p>
<p>Important experiments in institutional reform occurred, particularly in the education
sector. Qatar University was given independence from central government
and started efforts to strengthen research. Reform of the K-12 education
system began. The Supreme Education Council was established in 2003 to
spearhead reforms, overseeing the implementation of an independent school
model that was intended to extend choice and provide accountability for
performance.</p>
<p>Despite phenomenal economic success and notable progress across a range of
initiatives, stresses began to surface. From 2000 to 2007, Qatar&#x2019;s population doubled
in size. Citizens were increasingly becoming a minority in their own country and
faced challenges in preserving their cherished traditions and values. The country&#x2019;s
rapidly expanding population also put pressures on its natural resources and
environment.</p>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s public sector institutions had difficulty in keeping up with new and
expanding demands. The reality was that it was taking much longer to develop the
institutions and administrative capacities of a modern state than it had taken to
build an internationally competitive hydrocarbon industry. Increasing societal and
economic complexity called for flexible and responsive institutions, but Qatar&#x2019;s public
sector institutions, traditionally highly centralized, for the most part, remained rigid
and controlling. Gaps were opening in public sector service delivery. In response, a
comprehensive public sector reform program was introduced in 2008, with
the aim of rationalizing government and improving the quality of public
services.</p>
<p>Warding off economic volatility, too, proved a challenge. Price inflation began to
accelerate quickly in 2006 and, on the cusp of the global financial crisis in late 2008,
was running at over 15%. Though government planned its budget on the basis of
conservative oil price forecasts, which were normally well below realized prices,
public sector spending outcomes nevertheless moved in sync with oil prices
and revenues. This tended to accentuate volatility and created problems for
some spending agencies, such as the public works department, which had
difficulty in productively absorbing rapidly growing allocations. Another
casualty was the private sector, which had to cope with a lack of economic
predictability.</p>
<p>Though often quite successful in meeting their own goals, early diversification
and reform initiatives were necessarily bounded: they lacked linkages with
each other, did not permeate wider society and were highly dependent on
imported know-how and expertise. The unifying vision of Qatar&#x2019;s future needed
to support broader and more cohesive national efforts, which had yet to
emerge.</p>
<p>Recognizing the accelerated pace of change and the need to respond to emerging
challenges in a coordinated way, the leadership established the General Secretariat
for Development Planning (GSDP) in 2007. GSDP was given a mandate to provide
fresh thinking and strategic leadership on national development issues. Top political
approval of Qatar&#x2019;s National Vision 2030 (the Vision), launched in November 2008,
marked a watershed.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN3"><sup>1</sup></xref> The Vision (GSDP, 2008) superseded the twin-track
(hydrocarbon development plus &#x201C;pocket diversification&#x201D;) approach initially cultivated
in the mid-1990s. The Vision broke new ground by spelling out for the first time
what kind of country Qatar wanted to become, thereby signalling the choices that
Qatar intended to make. A beacon had been erected to guide the nation&#x2019;s
development.</p>
<p>The Vision reaffirmed the Constitution&#x2019;s commitment to a society that is safe
and just and which provides opportunities to its people. &#x201C;Sustainability
prosperity&#x201D;&#x2014;interpreted as the imperative of preserving wealth and leaving an
undiminished legacy to future generations&#x2014;anchored the Vision. The Vision set out
the broad economic, social, human and environmental attributes of sustainability,
and emphasized their interdependence.</p>
<p>The question of 
<italic>how</italic> to steer Qatar towards sustainable development is addressed by
Qatar&#x2019;s National Development Strategy 2011&#x2013;2016 (the Strategy), launched in March
2011.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN4"><sup>2</sup></xref> The Strategy started from what existed and drew extensively on the
knowledge of stakeholders. It called for systemic and sustainable responses to
challenges, recognizing the institutional transformations that this would
require.</p>
<p>Vision 2030 and the Strategy provide a framework to guide the future development of
the nation, but successful execution will require sweeping changes. Backed by top
leadership commitment, and the formation of the Supreme Committee for
Development Planning in 2011, many of the ingredients to support execution are
beginning to take root: new business processes to provide alignment and
coordination across the whole of government, incentives and tools to drive
performance and provide discipline and control, and the budgetary resources to
back projects. The Strategy&#x2019;s targets provide a bellwether for measuring
achievements in meeting the Vision&#x2019;s goals. Continuous monitoring, and periodic
reviews and evaluations will facilitate learning, refinements and mid-course
<!--\unskip \break -->adjustments.</p>
<p>From an economic perspective, progress towards sustainability requires that Qatar
graduate from an extractive and input (investment) focused economy to one in
which improvements in efficiency and productivity gains begin to impel
growth. Once efficiency and continuing productivity growth are embedded in
the economy, opportunities for diversification will widen and the goal of
harnessing and creating knowledge assets to drive economic advance will be
a step closer. Qatar has already made an impressive start, accomplishing
much in a short span of time. But a vibrant knowledge economy cannot
be created by the stroke of a pen. The capabilities, mindsets, networks,
institutions, incentives and infrastructure that are required will take time to
emerge.</p>
<p>The remainder of this review is divided into three sections.</p>
<p>First, the main factors that underpinned Qatar&#x2019;s success in the hydrocarbon&#x2019;s
industry are set out. The point is emphasized that success was not accidental but
followed from vision and well-executed, bold initiatives. Different factors were at play
in Qatar&#x2019;s successful development of LNG, GTL, oil and petrochemicals industries.
The lessons learned during this period about measured risk taking, planning and
building successful partnerships have resonance today and could be applied more
widely in helping Qatar diversify in the future.</p>
<p>Focussing largely on the period from 2000, the second section shows how Qatar put
its financial dividends from oil and gas to good use and how it has cultivated broader
institutional improvements. But while strong foundations have been laid for a
sustainable and prosperous future, progress is still partial, and securing
favourable outcomes will require that Qatar recognize and meet a number of new
challenges.</p>
<p>In the third section, the role that the Vision and Strategy play in charting Qatar&#x2019;s
future is set out. Economic prospects for the medium term (through to 2016) are first
described as are Strategy initiatives that will help Qatar to guard against risks.
Gazing farther out, the challenge of building a more diversified economy is discussed.
Here the point is stressed that an inclusive, knowledge and innovation-based
economy can only emerge from transformations that are embedded in broader
society.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>The story of hydrocarbons</title>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s achievements in oil and gas were not accidental, but the result of visionary
and ambitious strategies, bold decisions and good <!--\vadjust {\pagebreak }-->execution. The basic ingredients
that led to the success are summarized here.
<xref rid="fig1">Fig.&#x00A0;1</xref> provides a timeline of major developments dating from the discovery of the
North Field in 1971 through to 2015, when Qatar&#x2019;s Barzan project will have been
completed.
<fig  id="fig1">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;1.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Timeline of developments in Qatar&#x2019;s hydrocarbons sector.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr1.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig1}--></p>
<sec>
<title>The North Field</title>
<p>The large North Field gas reservoir was discovered in 1971. Its reservoir is the largest
non-associated natural gas field in the world, with reserves estimated in 2009 of over
900 trillion cubic feet (TCF) of gas, accounting for 14.3% of the world&#x2019;s proven
conventional gas reserves. But serious efforts to fully exploit the North Field&#x2019;s
abundant gas did not begin until the mid-1980s. Local demands for gas were at the
time satisfied by the associated gas from Qatar&#x2019;s oil production, and export outlets
were not immediately apparent. In the 1970s, gas was not perceived as a
valuable resource and much of the associated gas from oil was wasted in
flaring. An &#x201C;oil mentality&#x201D; prevailed in all GCC countries, including Qatar. In
general, there was significant local scepticism about the viability of North
Field gas and limited interest by international oil companies in exploitation.
Consequently, the financial resources needed to develop gas exports were not
available.</p>
<p>By the early 1980s the situation began to change. Natural gas was increasingly seen
as a valuable resource, but a variety of factors conspired to slow exploitation of the
North Field. The prevailing view was that while the reservoir should be tapped to
satisfy domestic needs and industrial opportunities, the processing and exporting of
gas in liquefied form, i.e., LNG, was likely to be technically and economically
infeasible.</p>
<p>But by 1984 the outline of the strategy was becoming clearer. Initially, development
would cater to the local market. But with the establishment of a joint venture to
construct a liquefaction facility, a decision had also been made to press ahead with
exports of LNG. Implicitly, the nation&#x2019;s top leadership had signalled its intent to
fully exploit the North Field. To realize the North Field&#x2019;s vast potential,
Qatar would need to overcome the challenge of selling its gas in distant
markets.</p>
<p>The years from 1985 to 1997&#x2014;the year in which Qatar&#x2019;s first LNG shipment reached
the shores of Japan&#x2014;were punctuated by strenuous efforts to overcome technical,
infrastructural, logistical, marketing and funding hurdles. Geopolitical developments
in the region and the shifting tides of energy demand in East Asia played their part
in the story.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Liquefied natural gas (LNG)</title>
<p>Early contacts with prospective buyers in Japan, who were looking for reliable and
competitive sources of long-run supply, brought the point home that Qatar&#x2019;s
advantages in gas&#x2014;a world-class resource, commitment to LNG development and
political stability&#x2014; were insufficient (<xref rid="fig2">Fig.&#x00A0;2</xref>). To serve the Japanese market, and to have a credible negotiating
position, Qatar would need dependable infrastructure, strong financial backing, and
experienced partners and management.
<fig  id="fig2">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;2.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Qatar&#x2019;s advantage in gas.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr2.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig2}--></p>
<p>To meet these requirements, but without any guarantees of success, Qatar&#x2019;s top
leadership (the then Heir Apparent, Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al Thani, now His
Highness the Emir Sheikh Hamad bin Khalifa Al Thani) gave the green light for the
creation of a giant gas hub at Ras Laffan, including a new world-class port. The
construction of this hub started in 1992 and was completed in 1996 at a cost
of about $2 billion US dollars. Partial funding for the development of the
North Field undertaking was obtained through forward sales of Qatar&#x2019;s crude
oil.</p>
<p>At the same time, Qatargas had to work hard to attract and keep financially solvent
and experienced partners on board. To achieve that, the state (Qatar Petroleum)
agreed to defer its royalties for gas feed until the project met hurdle rates of return
that partners saw as adequate. The final partners in Qatargas, in addition to Qatar
Petroleum, were ExxonMobil (Mobil at the time), Total, Marubini LNG International
and Mitsui LNG.</p>
<p>With strong technical and financial backing, and a world-class gas hub under
construction, Qatar acquired its first sales and purchase agreement (SPA) in 1992
with Chubu Electric. The agreement specified a quantity of 4 million tonnes
annually; the first shipment was delivered to Japan in early 1997.</p>
<p>With these developments, Qatar entered the Far East LNG market, where the price
of LNG was then high enough to justify the high cost of its LNG project and to allow
Qatar to meet its stringent financial obligations. Nevertheless, Qatar&#x2019;s location still
put it at a disadvantage relative to established regional suppliers of LNG,
such as Indonesia, Malaysia and Brunei. Moreover, the price of gas in other
major markets, particularly Europe, was not high enough to make Qatar&#x2019;s
LNG profitable. Even with higher prices, Qatar would have had difficulty in
competing against suppliers such as Algeria, Libya and Norway. At this
juncture, it had become apparent that to break into new markets and to
exploit its large reserve more fully, Qatar needed to find ways to become a
globally competitive LNG supplier, and to pursue other avenues for exporting
gas.</p>
<p>Becoming a competitive, global LNG supplier is easier said than done. In Qatar&#x2019;s
case, geography appeared to be a problem. Not being close to any major consuming
markets put Qatar at disadvantage relative to established regional players. But not
being far from any market, held out the tantalizing prospect of Qatar becoming a
supplier with global reach.</p>
<p>To achieve this, Qatar had to break new ground and accept calculated risks. Its
global strategy was built on three pillars: development and ownership of a fully
integrated LNG supply chain to capture value, leverage technology and economies of
scale to reduce cost, and build a reputation as a reliable and flexible supplier to prise
open new markets.</p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Qatar&#x2019;s integrated LNG model</italic></p>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s fully integrated LNG model is unique. It not only manages the gas reserve
and develops production and liquefaction facilities, it also incorporates shipping
and receiving terminal development into the project scope. In doing so, it
bridges the gap between the reservoir and the customer in ways that ensure
reliable and flexible cost-effective supplies. It provides the agility required to
benefit from price differentials across regional markets and the scope to
meet unanticipated customer needs. These levels of efficiency, agility and
responsiveness become feasible only when financial and technical strengths
align with the resources and leadership found in the State of Qatar and its
joint-venture partners. The essential elements of the model are summarized
<!--\unskip \break -->in
<xref rid="fig3">Fig.&#x00A0;3</xref>.
<fig  id="fig3">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;3.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; The integrated LNG model.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr3.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig3}--></p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Upstream</italic></p>
<p>Offshore, the opportunities for optimizing investment and applying advanced
technology begin with the need to maximize production on each wellhead platform
and optimize the offshore installations to minimize the amount of equipment and
associated operational and maintenance staff needed to manage the facilities.
RasGas&#x2019;s Train 3, and all later trains&#x2019; offshore installations took advantage of large
bore wells to maximize production on each platform. Additional optimization
involved moving the dehydration facilities out of the harsh offshore environment and
placing them onshore, next to the treating and liquefaction facilities. This placement
not only put the equipment closer to the shore-based maintenance staff, but also
eliminated the need to maintain offshore operational and maintenance staff and
support facilities.</p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Downstream</italic></p>
<p>The liquefaction plant forms the heart of any LNG project, and the prevailing plant
capacities in the 1990s were around 2 million tonnes. The size was dictated by the
high plant costs and the size of the sales and purchase agreements in end markets. A
large plant size translates into high plant capital costs and requires finding additional
buyers. Qatar led LNG suppliers in expanding plant capacity, using aggressive
financing and marketing strategies. In the space of a little over a decade, plant
capacity more than tripled (<xref rid="fig4">Fig.&#x00A0;4</xref>). In scaling up, Qatar deployed some of the cleanest and most efficient
technologies available (APX liquefaction<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN5"><sup>3</sup></xref> and frame 9E gas turbines), and tapped
synergies with existing plants. The upshot was that unit costs fell to a level
unmatched by other producers, giving Qatar a competitive edge in global
markets.
<fig  id="fig4">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;4.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Scaling up downstream.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr4.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig4}--></p>
<p><!--\pagebreak --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Shipping</italic></p>
<p>Another key to bridging the distance between supply and the end market was the
development of a new generation of LNG tankers. The capital costs of tankers
can exceed that of the liquefaction plant. And as shipping distances rise,
transport costs can eat into margins and have a significant impact on project
economics.</p>
<p>Qatar met these challenges by increasing the size of LNG vessels. This helped to reduce
the capital costs of the initial investment (as fewer ships were needed) and trimmed
operating costs. Qatar took the initiative in working with ship owners and builders to
develop and qualify LNG tankers, and cargo capacity increased from 209,000&#x00A0;<!--\xdollar\rm -->m<sup>3</sup><!--\xdollar--> (Q-Flex) up to 253,000&#x00A0;<!--\xdollar\rm -->m<sup>3</sup><!--\xdollar-->&#x00A0;(Q-Max)
(<xref rid="fig5">Fig.&#x00A0;5</xref>). These vessels incorporate twin, slow-speed diesel engines and on-board
re-liquefaction plants that will virtually eliminate cargo loss through LNG boil off.
This &#x201C;breakthrough&#x201D; in ship size technology and strategic partnerships with ship
builders was another critical step in helping Qatar realize its vision of becoming the
world&#x2019;s premier LNG supplier in the world.
<fig  id="fig5">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;5.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Economies in shipping.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr5.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig5}--></p>
<p><!--\pagebreak --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Marketing and branding</italic></p>
<p>Qatar adopted an aggressive marketing and branding strategy to complement its
initiatives in production and transportation. It quickly grasped that reliability,
flexibility, and loyalty to long-term customers would be essential to brand value. On
reliability, Qatar&#x2019;s motto was to deliver on time every time. On flexibility, Qatar was
willing to customize the sales and purchase agreements according to buyer&#x2019;s
needs. On loyalty, Qatar sought whenever possible to respond to long-term
buyers&#x2019; unexpected needs, i.e. requests for additional off-take, as a result
of interruptions of supply from other sources or from underestimation of
demand.</p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Outcomes</italic></p>
<p>As a result of this strategy, Qatar is now by far the largest supplier of LNG in the
world with 77 million tonnes of annual capacity. Its LNG supplies span the globe
reaching markets in Asia, Europe, North America, South America and Africa. Its
huge fleet of tankers efficiently moves its LNG cargoes to these markets and can
quickly divert supplies from one market to another, as needs change. A significant
portion of the LNG shipped by Qatar is re-gasified in receiving counties where Qatar
either co-owns terminals (Italy, UK and USA) or leases terminal capacity on a
long-term basis (Belgium).
<xref rid="fig6">Fig.&#x00A0;6</xref> shows the critical elements of Qatar&#x2019;s global LNG advantages now, which
may be compared with earlier advantages in
<xref rid="fig2">Fig.&#x00A0;2</xref>.
<fig  id="fig6">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;6.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Qatar&#x2019;s global LNG advantage.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr6.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig6}--></p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Gas-to-liquids fuels</title>
<p>Despite the superiority of natural gas to oil as an energy source in terms both of its
efficiency and its environmental impact, and as feed to petrochemical industries, it
has, nevertheless, played a subsidiary role to oil. High costs of transportation and
demanding infrastructure requirements have held back market penetration. Existing
technologies that are designed to work with liquids also render gas a poor substitute
for oil in road and air transportation.</p>
<p>In the past, these factors have influenced the relationship between the price of gas
and that of oil in two ways. The first is that the price of gas has been below parity
with oil in terms of its energy content (a barrel of oil has about six times more energy
than 1 million British Thermal Units of gas). Second, while gas prices have tended to
track oil prices over long intervals (albeit below par), the relationship has
frequently broken down in the short term. In recent times, prices in some markets
appear to have uncoupled, with gas prices sliding well below the price of
oil.</p>
<p>In the mid-1990s Qatar had the vision to realize the advantages of embracing GTL
both as a price hedge and as an additional opportunity for exploiting its huge gas
resources. At the time, the risks were significant. Commercial GTL production
required a significant scaling up of plant size (up to then, there were only two
existing GTL projects, both pilots), and, given the very large amount of capital
required, high oil prices (well in excess of the prices that oscillated around the $20
per barrel at a time) would be needed to break even. Qatar considered a number of
proposed projects between 2000 and 2004 and settled on two: ORYX GTL and Pearl
GTL.</p>
<p>ORYX GTL is a joint venture project with Sasol of South Africa. Construction began
in 2003 and production started up in 2007, with a capacity of 34,000 barrels of GTLs
annually. The Pearl GTL project, entailing a production-sharing agreement between
Qatar Petroleum and Shell, was on a much larger scale altogether. The Pearl project
has the capacity to produce 140,000 barrels per day (b/d) of premium GTL
products&#x2014;such as kerosene, diesel and naphtha&#x2014;and can deliver an additional
120,000 b/d of liquids such as condensate, LPG, and ethane. The Pearl GTL project
uses state-of-the-art, proprietary Shell technology, and is the largest GTL plant in
the world. The Pearl project was launched in 2006 and shipped its first cargo in
mid-2011&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b3">[3]</xref>.</p>
<p>Today, with high international oil prices but weak gas prices in the USA (a
consequence of large additions to supply from shale gas therein) market prospects are
much more promising for GTL. Qatar&#x2019;s successful penetration of wider energy
markets through GTL is further testimony to the leadership and the vision that has
guided exploitation of its gas resources.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Oil</title>
<p>Qatar has been and remains a modest producer of crude oil when compared
with its neighbours. During the 1970s, Qatar&#x2019;s oil production peaked at
around 500,000 b/d. As fields aged, production started to decline until it
reached around 300,000b/d in 1987. The results of exploration activities
proved disappointing and exploration acreage was relinquished for lack of
potential.</p>
<p>The 1990s witnessed a profound change in the strategy and management of Qatar&#x2019;s
crude oil business and exploration activities in general. Exploration, appraisal and
development opportunities were offered under production sharing agreements (PSAs)
in a number of fields.</p>
<p>The strategy to engage international oil companies (IOCs) through PSAs
represented a deviation from other OPEC countries&#x2019; policies. Qatar felt this
engagement was needed in fields that were costly and technologically difficult to
develop. Qatar Petroleum continued to directly manage operations in Qatar&#x2019;s
three largest fields. Such engagement held out the possibility of profitable
outcomes in fields that would otherwise have been fallow (dry). By being
transparent and by offering attractive returns to IOC&#x2019;s, Qatar attracted competent
partners.</p>
<p>The first success was with Al-Shaheen, where production started in 1994. The
Al-Shaheen reservoir eventually delivered the largest offshore reserves and production
in Qatar. This was followed by the Al-Rayaan and the Idd El Shargi South Dome
fields in 1996. Al-Karkara and A-Structures North Fields development followed
somewhat later in 2005.</p>
<p>As a result of these initiatives, Qatar&#x2019;s production of crude oil had more than
doubled by 2000. Total production stood at 682,000 b/d, of which 36% was from
PSA-developed fields, a major achievement considering that not a single barrel of oil
was produced before 1994 under such regimes. Thereafter, the production under
PSAs rose gradually to reach 50% of 2005&#x2019;s output of 760,000 b/d, with Al-Shaheen
field peaking at 300,000 b/d and Idd El Shargi North Dome at 100,000 b/d.
Production has oscillated around these levels until the present day (early
2012). Although these fields are still successfully operated by IOCs under
PSA regimes, the credit for the long-term strategy and overall reservoir
management belongs to Qatar Petroleum, which exercised prudent control over
reserves.</p>
<p>A major strategy rethink took place in 2005 about the fields under Qatar
Petroleum&#x2019;s direct operation. These fields were considered relatively simple to exploit
and provided back-up production in case of problems with PSA producers.
However, they had not been given the technical support and resources they
needed given their substantial contribution to total production and their
advancing maturity. As a result of this rethink, major reservoir and field-wide
studies were initiated to re-assess the reserves and the long-term production
prospects for each field. It is encouraging that the results of the first major
study of Bul Hanin field show significant addition to reserves, and pre-feed
development studies are ongoing. The results of the other two fields&#x2019; studies will
be completed by 2014. Re-development will be pursued if the results are
positive.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Petrochemicals</title>
<p>Prior to 1970, Qatar was flaring 80% of the associated gas that was produced as a
by-product of the production of oil. In the 1970s, Qatar started to use this flared gas
to build petrochemical and heavy industries. In 1973 it commissioned its first
fertilizer company in the Mesaeed area, where Qatar&#x2019;s first industrial city was built.
Ammonia and urea were produced using methane gas as feedstock. In 1978 Qatar
established a new petrochemical company, Qatar Petrochemical Company
(QAPCO). This company began the production of low-density polyethylene
(LDPE) in 1981, using ethane-rich gas as feed for the ethylene cracker. Gas
that would have otherwise been flared was also used for cement and steel
plants.</p>
<p>North Field gas then gave further impetus to the development of Qatar&#x2019;s
petrochemicals industry in the 1990s. Additional supplies of methane allowed
expansion of pre-existing capacity in ammonia and urea production. It also allowed
Qatar to move further downstream so as to manufacture new products such as
melamine. Increased volumes of ethane as well as investment in additional
ethylene crackers turned out low- and high-density polyethylene, and other
products such as ethylene dichloride, vinyl chloride monomer and normal alpha
olefin.</p>
<p>Projects currently under implementation will diversify Qatar&#x2019;s feedstock and,
for the first time, will produce propylene and butadiene. By 2020, Qatar&#x2019;s
petrochemicals industry will have been transformed in terms of depth as well as
scale, with production of 20 million tonnes, up from 9 million tonnes in
2011.</p>
<p>As in the LNG case, Qatar used the joint venture model to develop its petrochemical
industry&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b4">[4]</xref>. It was able to attract reputable foreign partners because
of its readily available feedstock, its favourable investment climate, and its
understanding of partners&#x2019; interests. Qatar selected its partners on the basis of their
expertise in marketing the specific products and the terms on which access was
provided to their proprietary technologies. Most of these partners were IOCs who
already had positive relationships with Qatar in upstream and downstream
businesses.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Summary</title>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s hydrocarbons development provides a fascinating study in industrial
economics. Massive investments that were made under highly uncertain conditions
paid off handsomely. The ingredients of success bear repeating: decisive leadership,
far-sighted strategy, astute risk management, smart business models attuned to needs
at home and in distant markets and a resolute commitment to execution. They all
combined to make it happen. The partnerships, planning, systems and processes that
drove progress hold important lessons for Qatar as it strives to become a knowledge
economy.</p>
<p>In the next section, the economic and wider impacts of Qatar&#x2019;s success in
hydrocarbons are described.</p>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Economic performance</title>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s economic ascent has been telescoped into a remarkably short space of time.
The hydrocarbon industry has been the locomotive that has driven a remarkable
transformation. Impacts are etched on a variety of indicators.</p>
<sec>
<title>GDP growth</title>
<p>From 2000 and 2011, Qatar&#x2019;s real GDP expanded at an annual average rate of 13.1%.
Much of this expansion occurred from 2004 to 2011, when GDP growth averaged
15.9% a year. Globally, Qatar&#x2019;s economic growth has been without parallel,
outstripping even that of China (<xref rid="fig7">Fig.&#x00A0;7</xref>). When expressed in units of purchasing power, GDP per capita in Qatar
in 2010 ranked first globally among 182 countries.
<fig  id="fig7">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;7.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; GDP growth in Qatar.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr7.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig7}--></p>
<p>While hydrocarbons&#x2019; activity has been in the vanguard of growth, its development
has had beneficial knock-on impacts on the rest of the economy (<xref rid="fig8">Fig.&#x00A0;8</xref>), as Qatar&#x2019;s non-oil and gas economy has also grown apace.
<fig  id="fig8">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;8.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Sector contributions to growth.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr8.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig8}--></p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Fiscal, payments and financial sector performance</title>
<p>Other yardsticks of economic performance are equally impressive. Qatar has
consistently posted large fiscal and current account surpluses, often exceeding 10% of
GDP (<xref rid="fig9">Fig.&#x00A0;9</xref>). Its total saving has averaged 56% of GDP and investment around 33%
over the same period. In recent years, Qatar has been investing 10% of GDP on
economic and social infrastructure.
<fig  id="fig9">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;9.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Fiscal and current account balances (% of GDP).</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr9.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig9}--></p>
<p>From modest beginnings, Qatar&#x2019;s banking and financial sector has thrived. Bank
assets have grown from a mere QR92 billion in 2004 to QR694 billion by the end of
2011, with the ratio of bank assets to GDP climbing to 110% from 80% over the same
period (<xref rid="fig10">Fig.&#x00A0;10</xref>). A variety of measures attest to domestic financial strength and
resilience. Qatar attracts the highest sovereign credit rating of all countries in the
region. Finally, although the state does not publish information on the country&#x2019;s net
international financial position, total net overseas investments plus foreign exchange
reserves are estimated at about $200 billion.
<fig  id="fig10">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;10.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Ratio of commercial banks assets to GDP.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr10.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig10}--></p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Competitiveness and doing business</title>
<p>A raft of indicators suggests an economy that is on the move (<xref rid="fig11">Fig.&#x00A0;11</xref>). The World Bank&#x2019;s 
<italic>Doing Business</italic> survey placed Qatar at 36
out of 183 countries in 2011.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN6"><sup>4</sup></xref> Switzerland&#x2019;s IMD&#x2019;s 
<italic>Global Competitiveness
Yearbook</italic> of 2012 ranked Qatar as the tenth most competitive country out of the
59 countries surveyed.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN7"><sup>5</sup></xref> Qatar has steadily climbed the ranks of the World
Economic Forum&#x2019;s 
<italic>Global Competitiveness Index</italic>, to 14 out of 142 countries
in the 2011&#x2013;2012 survey.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN8"><sup>6</sup></xref> Qatar&#x2019;s progress is indicated in other surveys
as well; for example, INSEAD&#x2019;s 
<italic>Global Innovation Index</italic> sees the country
making steady headway, easily ahead in the Arab world and ranking 26th
globally.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN9"><sup>7</sup></xref>
<fig  id="fig11">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;11.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; How Qatar compares on business, competitiveness and innovation.</title> 
</caption>
<graphic xlink:href="gr11.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>    
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig11}--></p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Policy, institutions and governance</title>
<p>Behind these favourable indicators lies progress on policy and institutional reform.
Qatar is an open economy with few impediments to trade or investment. Qatar
maintains low nominal tariffs on imports, with most tariff lines at 5% or less. In
2000, Qatar began to ease restrictions on direct foreign investment (outside
of oil and gas). Although majority Qatari ownership is required in some
sectors, 100% foreign ownership is permitted in a growing list of sectors
including industry, agriculture, health, tourism, education, energy, mining and
service sectors. In addition, 100% foreign ownership is permitted in the special
economic zones of the Qatar Financial Centre and Qatar Foundation (including
tenants of the Qatar Science and Technology Park). Qatar has also successfully
trialled public-private partnership initiatives in its power and water sector.
Modern anti-trust (and consumer protection) legislation was promulgated in
2004.</p>
<p>Institutional advances have shown through in governance, and improvements are
on-going as discussed elsewhere in this paper. Operationally, there is now an
emphasis within the public sector on performance (rather than inputs) and the
creation of &#x201C;value for money&#x201D;. A significant rationalization and reorganization of the
functions of ministries and agencies is underway. These are directed toward
improving service delivery, eliminating waste and enhancing accountability. An
initiative of particular importance has been expanding the role of the former Finance
Ministry to include economic policy support, advice and coordination. In recognition
of this expanded role, in 2008 the Ministry was renamed the Ministry of Economy
and Finance.</p>
<p>Measures of the quality of governance hint at a strengthening of the institutional
base for development. In five out of six categories, the World Bank&#x2019;s governance
metrics&#x2014;aggregating information from an extensive range of sources&#x2014;place Qatar in
the top 30% of performers globally.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN10"><sup>8</sup></xref> In Transparency International&#x2019;s index of public
sector corruption, Qatar ranks 22, placing it alongside the ranks of developed OECD
countries.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN11"><sup>9</sup></xref></p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Economic structure and diversification</title>
<p>As noted, Qatar&#x2019;s non-oil and gas economy has also grown rapidly, averaging nearly
20% from 2004 to 2011. But much of this expansion would not have occurred without
hydrocarbons. Construction, utilities and downstream transport services
(margins from the shipment of LNG) all grew in response to the needs of a
booming hydrocarbon sector. Growth in the petrochemical sector and in some
energy-intensive activities was made possible by the availability of cheap
feedstock.</p>
<p>Sizeable government spending funded from hydrocarbon proceeds has also had
knock-on effects on the wider non-oil and gas economy. A large infrastructure push
(<xref rid="fig12">Fig.&#x00A0;12</xref>) and the expansion of public services to cater to the needs of a much
larger resident population are two channels through which expansion of
fiscal activity has reverberated across the wider economy. Domestic trading
activity has benefitted from rapid population growth and rising aggregate
income.
<fig  id="fig12">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;12.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Qatar&#x2019;s spending on infrastructure.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr12.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig12}--></p>
<p>But not all boats have been lifted equally by the rising tide of hydrocarbons income.
The scale of activities in some other parts of the economy has remained
small. In particular, industrial activity that does not derive advantage from
the availability of feedstock or inexpensive energy has remained negligible
from a macro perspective. In 2010, only two such manufacturing product
categories recorded exports of more than QR100 million, compared to overall
exports (including hydrocarbons) of QR290 billion. A study of new exports
from Qatar also shows that less than 50% of Qatar&#x2019;s exports survive one
year after their introduction.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN12"><sup>10</sup></xref> Although exports of some products (such
as valves and motor parts) are now sprouting, the values involved are still
small.</p>
<p>Despite the stimulus that hydrocarbon investment and production has given to the
rest of the economy, a more diverse economy has yet to emerge.</p>
<p>Accepted measures of 
<italic>output</italic> diversification suggest that in 2011, Qatar was only
marginally more diversified than it was in 2004 (<xref rid="fig13">Fig.&#x00A0;13</xref>). Indeed, the output share of hydrocarbons for 2011 has risen with the
completion of LNG investments and the commissioning of the Pearl GTL
plant&#x00A0;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="b5">[5]</xref>. The share of output contributed by the private sector
remains small. Export revenue diversification has also been slow, with well over 95%
of total receipts flowing from oil and gas. <!--\setFloat [h]{fig13}--> Nevertheless, and in response to earlier
fiscal initiatives, progress has been made in diversifying Qatar&#x2019;s fiscal revenues
(<xref rid="fig14">Fig.&#x00A0;14</xref>). Adjustments to corporation tax in 2010 temporarily distort the
picture. The accumulation of assets by the Qatar Investment Authority will
contribute to the future diversification of Qatar&#x2019;s income.
<fig  id="fig13">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;13.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Composition of real output.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr13.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<fig  id="fig14">  
<label>Figure&#x00A0;14.</label>  
<caption> 
<title>&#x00A0; Structure of fiscal revenue.</title> 
</caption>       
<graphic xlink:href="gr14.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>      
</fig>
<!--\setFloat [h]{fig14}--></p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Building on achievements</title>
<p>In summary, a variety of indicators confirm remarkable economic progress,
particularly since 2000. These achievements have been accompanied by policy and
institutional improvements. Economic gains have also helped to make possible wider
social progress. For example, Qatar has universal enrolment of boys and girls in
primary and secondary education, and child mortality rates have dropped
dramatically. In 2011, Qatar ranked 37th on the United Nations Human Development
Index, out of 187 countries.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN13"><sup>11</sup></xref></p>
<p>But the remarkable pace of change on the macro scale has not been matched by
transformations at a structural or micro level. Here, Qatar&#x2019;s economy has been slower
to change. In the years ahead, Qatar will be working to create the fabric of a more
efficient, productive and resilient economy, and to lay the foundations for new sources
of wealth creation that are knowledge and innovation based. These issues are now
taken up.</p>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Looking ahead</title>
<sec>
<title>Medium-term prospects</title>
<p>A sea change in hydrocarbons momentum is now under way. The steep ascent of the
past decade has run its course and hydrocarbons output will now plateau. This is not
an unexpected development. It has been programmed in the sequence of investment
made over the past two decades and in the decision in 2005 to put a hold on new gas
projects in the North Field.</p>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s oil production may have already peaked, though opportunities for stemming
declines through incremental and enhanced oil recovery are being studied. No new
gas projects other than Barzan&#x2014;which will start up in 2014/2015&#x2014;are planned, and
upstream production will remain more or less flat. Growth in oil and gas
output of 16% in 2011 is expected to make way in 2012 to growth of just
3%, with low single-digit growth continuing through to at least 2016. The
profile of depletion and production beyond this timeframe is not known.
However, current levels of production set a lower bound for the foreseeable
future.</p>
<p>With these developments, Qatar&#x2019;s non-oil and gas economy is now set to take over
the reins of growth.</p>
<p>In high-value services, further expansion is penned in. The opening of the new Doha
International Airport, and the expansion plans of Qatar Airways&#x2014;which is
anticipating rapid passenger volume growth over the next decade&#x2014;will add to output
and exports. Improved regional and international connectivity, the completion of
state of the art conference facilities and expansion of hotel accommodation should
support continuing growth of business tourism.</p>
<p>Despite difficult conditions in the global financial economy, Qatar&#x2019;s financial sector
will continue to expand and support growth in the wider economy. The Qatar
Financial Centre Authority is actively promoting development of asset management,
captive insurance and re-insurance businesses. Qatar Exchange, the country&#x2019;s stock
exchange, is launching new trading platforms. A &#x201C;junior bourse&#x201D; will soon open to
provide better access to equity finance for smaller businesses. Secondary trading of
government paper and issuance of securities of longer maturity will support the
development of a domestic corporate debt market and 
<italic>sukuk</italic> (Islamic financial
bonds). The commercial banking sector, both conventional and Islamic, is
expected to enjoy healthy growth in its retail business, and will have the
opportunity to participate in the funding of a substantive pipeline of capital
projects.</p>
<p>In industry, the expansion of downstream activity will be temporarily constrained by
the availability of feedstock. De-bottlenecking and other measures that expand
supply of feedstock may provide some scope for expansion, but until Barzan comes on
stream in 2014/15, this is expected to be modest. In manufacturing activities that are
not linked to oil and gas (or energy), there may be pockets of rapid growth, but
typically from a low base. The efforts of Qatar&#x2019;s export development agency
(Tasdeer) to support non-oil and gas exports, and new initiatives of the Qatar
Development Bank and Enterprise Qatar to support fledgling small and
medium-sized enterprise (SME) activity through the provision of financial and
non-financial support services, will start to bear fruit. More generally, the removal of
regulatory impediments to business, improved logistics services, easier access to
credit, wider availability of equity funding, and subsidized support services
(including for export promotion) will support private enterprise across a broader
front.</p>
<p>Other sectors, too, will see some expansion. Government services, utilities and retail
and other domestic services will need to keep up with overall pace of growth in the
economy and an anticipated increase in population.</p>
<p>But the mainstay of Qatar&#x2019;s economic growth over the medium term will be large
infrastructure spending. Estimates of the total amount of spending vary, but are
in a range of between $100 billion to $150 billion over the interval from
2012 to 2015/16. The IMF estimates that central government will directly
finance $100 billion of capital expenditure over this period, equivalent to 10%
of expected cumulative nominal GDP.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN14"><sup>12</sup></xref> This is a statistic that has been
matched by few, if any, countries. Resources are tagged for a broad array of
projects: the Doha Metro and ancillary infrastructure; GCC and internal rail
links; road expansion and upgrading; the new Doha sea port; expansion of
the water collection networks and treatment plants; mega reservoirs; urban
redevelopment projects; industrial zones; and new stadiums and other facilities for
the 2022 FIFA World Cup. To be added to these are current and new real
estate projects, investments by Qatar Foundation, and any new industrial
projects. However, direct government financing for these latter activities is not
anticipated.</p>
<p>When all these prospective developments are pieced together, robust GDP
growth, in a range of 5%&#x2013;7% per year, is expected through to 2016. Within
this aggregate, the hydrocarbons sector is expected to average in growth
at a rate of about 1 percentage point, with the non-hydrocarbons sector
contributing the remainder. It is anticipated that the non-hydrocarbons sector will
grow at between 9&#x2013;10% per annum. This profile of growth implies that by
2016 the share of non-hydrocarbons in aggregate output will be 64%, up
from 55% in 2011. Substantial fiscal and balance of payments&#x2019; surpluses will
continue, though they will narrow somewhat by rising public spending and
imports.</p>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s ambitious investment plans lay a solid foundation for the future, but realizing
their full potential will require that government steer a path that is both sustainable
and provides for stability in the short term. A variety of risks present themselves.
Spending on the scale anticipated could create bottlenecks and congestion and add to
material and project costs. The liquidity created through the financing of sizeable
capital projects could present challenges for monetary management and the control of
inflation. And if hydrocarbon income were to be squeezed by falling oil prices, fiscal
surpluses could narrow.</p>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s Strategy sets out targets for improved fiscal planning and management that
will help attenuate risks. The Ministry of Economy and Finance is now establishing
the processes needed to support a forward-looking budget aligned with national
development priorities. To help preserve stability, Qatar is working to strengthen its
frameworks for liquidity management and macro-prudential monitoring. In
2011, the Ministry of Economy and Finance started to issue Treasury Bills,
which are now being used to control liquidity in the domestic economy, and
will contribute to wider efforts to build a corporate bond market in local
currency.</p>
<p>To help ensure effective project execution and delivery, the Ministry of Municipality
and Urban Planning has established a central planning unit. This unit will
coordinate implementation of all major national infrastructure projects,
including those being implemented outside of government by entities such as
Qatari Diar and the Qatar Railway Company. This initiative should help to
reduce project delays and cost overruns and lessen risks of coordination
difficulties.</p>
<p>Drawing lessons from the past, Qatar&#x2019;s National Development Strategy also stresses
the need for rigorous upstream assessment of large capital projects, scrutinizing needs
and alternative service delivery models (including through public-private
partnerships) and evaluating their likely economic, social and environment impacts.
Increasingly, government will review and select significant capital spending projects
within an integrated, national portfolio perspective. This innovation will help to
increase the likelihood of beneficial outcomes, reduce project risks and ensure that
there are adequate fiscal resources to support capital assets over their extended
lifetimes.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>The medium-term development agenda</title>
<p>Economic growth will continue to be input driven over the medium term, but the job
of building <!--\unskip \break -->the foundations of a more efficient, diversified and innovative economy
will at the same time gather pace.</p>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s Vision looks to a future that sustains high standards of living, safeguards
economic and financial stability, and provides a solid foundation for prosperity
through expanded innovation and entrepreneurial capabilities. Today, the World
Economic Forum classifies Qatar&#x2019;s economy as one in transition from factor (input)
driven economic growth to one in which efficiency and productivity advances
come more to the fore. As the Strategy observes, inefficiency and lagging
productivity in Qatar&#x2019;s non-oil and gas economy are serious weaknesses,
but, equally, closing gaps constitutes an opportunity to stimulate future
growth.</p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Enhancing efficiency and stimulating productivity growth</italic></p>
<p>There are many reasons for the inefficient use of resources. Some are purely technical.
For example, the Strategy identifies solutions that would save 5% and possibly more
of domestic gas consumption. The Strategy also shows how better delivery
mechanisms could save water and add value to infrastructure. Fixing these
problems over the next five years, combined with measures to encourage
the adoption of more efficient technologies, will bring long-term benefits to
Qatar in terms of cost reductions, resource conservation and a smaller carbon
footprint.</p>
<p>But the causes of inefficiency go deeper than technical faults and the use of
outmoded technologies. Regulatory and administrative encumbrances often prevent
resources getting put to their best use, diminish the quality of services and raise their
costs. For example, while showing some improvement, the time and money costs of
establishing and operating a business in Qatar are still very high. In impeding the
flow of goods, burdensome customs regulations and procedures also raise the cost of
doing business in Qatar. The Ministry of Business and Trade is now implementing a
programme to streamline regulations and procedures, discarding those that serve no
purpose. Such reforms are expected to be of general benefit but should assist SMEs
in particular.</p>
<p>Other regulatory advances are in the pipeline. Approval of Qatar&#x2019;s National
Master Plan, will herald a new approach to land use planning and regulation.
Among other things, implementation of the Plan should improve SME access
to well-serviced industrial land, currently a major constraint to start-ups.
Special economic zones, operating within their own regulatory provisions
and providing access to first-class infrastructure services, will also be a step
forward.</p>
<p>Various metrics show that Qatar&#x2019;s productivity (output produced per unit input) in
the non-oil and gas sector is sagging. In most sectors it took more workers to produce
a set level of output in 2011 than it did back in 2006. This is in marked contrast to
virtually all successful emerging economies, where output per worker advances on an
upward trajectory.</p>
<p>The Strategy attributes poor performance on productivity in the non-oil and gas
economy to policies that perpetuate low demands for skill and knowledge within a
more varied economy. In particular, current sponsorship and immigration regulations
encourage employers to orient their recruitment and production strategies around the
availability of a large pool of cheap, lesser skilled immigrant workers. Regulations
restrict expatriate workers from moving jobs and remove the growth dividend that
occurs when workers move from lower- to higher-productivity jobs. The Strategy calls
for a rethink of policies that have fostered dependence on lesser-skilled, low-wage
labour. While some adjustment costs would be incurred in a move to a higher-wage,
higher-productivity economy, the persistence of arrangements that favour
labour-intensive production methods is at odds with Qatar&#x2019;s goal of becoming a more
diverse, knowledge-based economy.</p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Supporting private sector development</italic></p>
<p>The contribution of the private sector to Qatar&#x2019;s economy is small, and the sector has
shown little dynamism over the past decade. Over half of all small manufacturing
enterprises that exist today were in business before 2000. As noted, low levels of
efficiency and competition permeate the sector. Very few private firms, outside of oil
and gas, produce and compete in regional or global markets. Most activity faces
inwards. Transforming the private sector so that it can provide attractive economic
opportunities for citizens and contribute to Qatar&#x2019;s diversification agenda is a
priority.</p>
<p>The reasons for private sector weakness are many. Historically, responsibility was
thrust on the state to build the infrastructure and services needed to support oil and
gas development. State-owned enterprises (SOEs) delivered services in the absence of
a capable private sector. This approach made sense at the time but entrenched
SOEs now foil opportunities for Qatar&#x2019;s fledgling private sector. Plans to
divest non-core SOEs and to liberalize state procurement regulations will
mean that the private sector can now look forward to expanded business
opportunities.</p>
<p>For a long time, support for Qatar&#x2019;s private sector was piecemeal and coordination
was lacking. Enterprise Qatar (EQ), a one-stop development agency for local
business, is now starting to fill that gap. EQ packages and puts advisory, business
support and financial services within reach of SMEs by underwriting their costs. Its
business model works by stimulating delivery by private sector service providers and,
in doing so, it aims to strengthen the overall &#x201C;eco-system&#x201D; within which SMEs and
the private sector operate. In the future, Enterprise Qatar will also actively mobilize
equity capital.</p>
<p>Qatar Development Bank (QDB), once a traditional public sector bank focussed on
direct lending to eligible industrial clients at subsidized interest rates, is now
re-orienting its services to serve a wider base of SME clients in new ways. Tasdeer, an
offshoot of QDB, is helping to identify and remove impediments to exporting
activity at the business unit and product level, and is expanding its export
credit guarantee facilities. QDB is also partnering with other organizations
to support grass-roots initiatives that foster entrepreneurship among the
young.</p>
<p>In many parts of Qatar&#x2019;s non-oil and gas economy, stiff barriers to entry have
obstructed private sector development, despite anti-trust legislation. Qatar&#x2019;s 2004
competition law exempts SOEs from its requirements. Its provisions on competition
are also largely dormant as effective implementing mechanisms are yet to be
established. The playing field is uneven in other ways too. State procurement
regulations favour larger, established entities at the expense of start-ups and small
businesses. Bid bonds, for example, are often so large that they dwarf available
working capital, and small businesses have difficulty in accessing bank credit. Some
state-owned entities, such as the Qatar Tourist Authority, compete against the
private sector firms that they regulate. A variety of measures that will help to level
the playing field and promote competition have now been identified by the Ministry
of Business and Trade.</p>
<p>The Strategy emphasizes the need for an enabling framework to promote
public-private partnerships (PPPs). In terms of capital projects, Qatar&#x2019;s interest in
PPPs stems primarily from the planning, technical, implementation and operational
expertise that private partners can offer and the beneficial impacts of this expertise
on local capabilities and service quality. Large savings in costs can also be expected
to follow from PPP arrangements. An expanding PPP deal flow would also provide
opportunities for Qatar&#x2019;s financial sector. While Qatar may not need PPPs to fill
funding gaps, agreements that require private partners to fairly share risks will
provide an incentive for strong performance. Qatar is in the process of framing
policies and laws that will help ensure that PPP&#x2019;s can deliver lasting benefits to the
economy.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Imperative of diversification</title>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Why diversify?</italic></p>
<p>From a narrow financial perspective, one might ponder why diversification is
necessary, and why Qatar should aspire to become an innovation-driven economy.
Some believe that for several generations to come, Qatar should have few
financial worries. So why the urgency about economic diversification? The
rationale underpinning the Vision and the Strategy provides three compelling
answers.</p>
<p>First, a strategy focused exclusively on building a financial endowment could
foreshadow a future in which income levels are high but in which Qataris&#x2019;
capabilities, creativity, resilience and even &#x201C;happiness&#x201D; are undermined. It
would also leave Qatar vulnerable to the vagaries of international capital
markets or even to forms of investment &#x201C;protectionism&#x201D; emerging in host
countries. Investment of wealth overseas certainly provides one avenue of 
<italic>income</italic>
diversification and a safety valve that shields the domestic economy from potentially
destabilizing large financial inflows, but, on its own, it is an inadequate 
<italic>development</italic>
strategy.</p>
<p>Second, the future is simply unknowable. In 1971, at the dawn of independence,
Qatar&#x2019;s contemporary circumstances would have been unimaginable. Tomorrow&#x2019;s
reality could again surprise. Risks that might undermine the value of Qatar&#x2019;s
hydrocarbons&#x2019; resources cannot simply be wished away. For example, large finds of
unconventional (shale) gas is potentially a game changer in global energy markets. In
the event that adverse shocks were to materialize, Qatar&#x2019;s window for economic
diversification could narrow dramatically. As the process of discovering where
competitive <!--\unskip \break -->advantage lies entails significant learning and experimentation, a &#x201C;wait
and see&#x201D; approach could prove costly.</p>
<p>Third, passively accepting dependence on hydrocarbons poses a threat to stability.
Historically, such dependence has heightened economic volatility, presenting
challenges for economic management and private sector development. In
extreme form, economic volatility could prove socially disruptive. Economic
diversification mitigates these risks and in doing so helps to reset underlying
socioeconomic dynamics. With lower levels of economic volatility, the climate for
investment improves and &#x201C;economic discovery&#x201D;&#x2014; the process whereby nations
acquire and develop the knowledge, skills and technology needed to enter and
succeed in new economic activities&#x2014;can more easily gain traction and become
self-sustaining.</p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>How to diversify</italic></p>
<p>In some countries, governments have chosen the exact path of diversification,
earmarking specific industries and creating incentives and directives for private
investors to follow. In Qatar, selectivity is implied by the Vision&#x2019;s aspirations.
Economic activities that risk undercutting the Vision&#x2019;s goals are discouraged. But
this leaves the door open for a wide array of economic activities that can potentially
contribute to Qatar&#x2019;s wider development agenda.</p>
<p>The precise areas in which economic and commercial advantage will occur cannot be
pinpointed accurately. Some countries may have had success in &#x201C;picking winners&#x201D;,
but costly, state-supported industrial misadventures have been the experience of
many others. In Qatar, economic advantage outside of oil and gas will emerge from a
process in which many actors are involved in search, experimentation, failure,
learning and successful discovery. Government support for new <!--\unskip \break -->economic activities
will have a role to play, but on an experimental rather than an expansive, industrial
scale.</p>
<p>While the government&#x2019;s role in targeting investment from the top will be
bounded, it will, nevertheless, be instrumental in fostering the development of
a more diverse, knowledge-based economy. Many of the required enabling
ingredients can only be provided by government, and only government can resolve
coordination problems and orchestrate decentralized actions among assorted
actors.</p>
<p>In looking at potential opportunities for diversification, it makes good sense to start
with hydrocarbons. A three-pronged strategy suggests itself in this part of the
economy&#x2014;leveraging value; diversifying and hedging price and market risks, and
expanding expertise. However, outside of activities connected with hydrocarbons,
opportunities to diversify through industrialization are limited, and many industrial
activities would likely fall short in terms of meeting Qatar&#x2019;s broader development
needs. <!--\pagebreak --></p>
<p><!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Hydrocarbons&#x2019; opportunities</italic></p>
<p>Qatar will continue to leverage downstream advantages linked to hydrocarbons.
Activities that add value to feedstock through additional processing will be of
benefit. The state profits through equity participation and production- or
profit-sharing arrangements, or through suitable fiscal arrangements that
provide income in excess of what would have been obtained had the feedstock
been exported. Benefits from risk diversification and stability follow when
the prices of downstream processed products are less volatile than (and
possibly delinked from or even inversely correlated with) underlying prices
upstream. Exposure to new technologies, processes and expertise downstream will
also help to expand Qatar&#x2019;s economic horizons. Several projects are now in
process including a new petrochemical complex in Ras Laffan Industrial City
(starting in 2016). Qatar Petroleum International is also diversifying Qatar&#x2019;s
interests by making strategic commercial investments in the energy value chain
globally, including petrochemicals in Singapore and Vietnam, production in
Mauritania, and receiving terminals in the United Kingdom, Italy and the United
States.</p>
<p>Qatar is also looking to increase the pay-off from its gas resources through
integration along the energy supply chain. Qatar&#x2019;s participation in the GCC&#x2019;s
interconnectivity grid project will expand the market for the country&#x2019;s surplus
power and, through sharing of regional generation capacity, may also provide
more flexibility in meeting future domestic energy needs. Depending on
market structure and pricing agreements, a regional grid could add to the
value of Qatar&#x2019;s gas and could also provide some decoupling from volatile oil
prices.</p>
<p>For the GCC as a whole, there are wider opportunities. Off-peak demand and spare
capacity in the region coincides with periods of peak demand during European
winters. The extension of the grid using a high voltage line through a suitable
gateway would offer the possibility of selling electricity in European wholesale
markets. Given Qatar&#x2019;s low costs of generation and Europe&#x2019;s high peak-load prices,
this would create significant value. And with increased power generation in winter
months, Qatar could step up its production of desalinated water to replenish its
aquifers or allocate it to other uses that have high social value (perhaps in high
value-added agronomy).</p>
<p>Qatar&#x2019;s low-cost power also creates potential diversification opportunities in other
areas, including in high-value, speciality steels, particularly those that are used in the
oil and gas business and in automotive industries. Qatar is well positioned to explore
these opportunities with national and international oil companies, and with the oil
service industry in places like Singapore.</p>
<p>However, outside the natural gas/crude oil and energy value chain, opportunities for
industrialization and assembly-line goods production look less promising. The size of
Qatar&#x2019;s domestic market, its demography, its real exchange rate dynamics (which
create pressures that result in a high domestic cost base for manufacturing industry)
and its location (distant from markets and trading routes) are impediments to
the development of competitive manufacturing activities linked to global
supply chains. Therefore the path of climbing the manufacturing value-added
ladder and gradually branching out towards more sophisticated product
groups&#x2014;the path taken by successful emerging economies in East Asia&#x2014;is unlikely
to be one that Qatar can easily follow. The attractions of this route for
Qatar are also limited as new assembly-line jobs are not what citizens aspire
to.</p>
<p><!--\medskip --> <!--\smallskip\noindent --><italic>Knowledge-driven opportunities</italic></p>
<p>The location, cost, market and other constraints that place boundaries on Qatar&#x2019;s
industrial potential (outside of oil/gas and energy complex) do not present the same
impediments to economic activities in which value originates in the ownership and
control of intellectual assets. Such assets might include proprietary technologies,
designs, brands, processes, media and other forms of content. Similarly, obstacles to
the competitive production of traded manufactured goods do not apply to service
activities in which value is created through leveraging a high-octane mix of
technology and human capital.</p>
<p>For Qatar, knowledge-intensive economic activities have strong appeal. The list of
attractions is long: they are not dependent on, or linked to, oil and gas; they
have significant export potential; they can provide decent and productive
jobs and business opportunities for citizens outside of the public sector, and
they offer ample opportunities for life-long development of capabilities. Such
activities also make few demands on natural resources or the environment
and do not require heavy immigration of unskilled workers. In short, they
offer the potential for sustainable improvements in standards of living that
are in harmony with the human, social and environmental goals of Qatar&#x2019;s
Vision.</p>
<p>For Qatar, advantages might present themselves in a number of areas. These could
include cleaner and renewable (solar and wind) energy, low-carbon technologies,
biosciences, smart materials, and sustainable water technologies. Given the
country&#x2019;s advantages in energy, and its compactness, the development of
cleaner transportation solutions (electric or hydrogen-based) might also be
promising. In services, the list of possible opportunities is long and would include,
but is not limited to, the following: tertiary education; healthcare; media;
IT and communications; finance, banking and insurance; environmental
services; professional services, and some niche tourism (such as business and
sports).</p>
<p>However, to build advantage in these and other areas, Qatar will need to create an
&#x201C;eco-system&#x201D; in which knowledge activities can germinate, incubate and grow. The
elements of such which are many, and it is important that they work in a unified way.
Qatar has already made a good start with Qatar Foundation and other
initiatives, but cultivating a society in which knowledge and innovation becomes
widely diffused and provides a robust platform for wealth creation will take
time.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Towards an innovation eco-system</title>
<p>Beyond 2016 and moving toward 2030, Qatar&#x2019;s attention will increasingly turn to
creating a fertile, innovation eco-system. Some elements of this system already exist;
some are under construction; but others are yet to get started. Forming the
connective tissue that will bind the system and help it to function in a unified and
synergistic way is also a job for the future.</p>
<p>While successful innovation eco-systems in advanced countries have their
distinctive traits and histories, there are some ingredients that are common to
success.</p>
<p>The wider economic and social environment within which systems evolve is
critical. Without a flexible and efficient economy, innovation is unlikely to
prosper. The nation&#x2019;s education system must equip citizens with the relevant
skills and mindsets that will allow their active participation in the wider
economy. Society needs to be open to ideas and be able to attract and retain
highly talented people. While innovation systems may be geographically
localized, their actors need to be connected to the wider world and have a global
outlook.</p>
<p>Cultivating innovation will place high demands on government. Public institutions
will need to become more responsive and flexible, and capable of delivering high
quality services efficiently. Increasingly, state-directed, top-down relationships will
need to make way for effective collaboration and partnerships among government, the
private sector and other actors. It will also be imperative that policy, laws
and regulations become attuned to the demands of an economy in which
property is embodied in ideas, in which enormous scale economies limit
competition and increase the return to strategic behaviour, and in which
commerce and exchange occurs in virtual as well as real space. Implementing
responsibilities need to be located in competent agencies that have political
authority.</p>
<p>As markets alone cannot promote economic discovery, public financial support for
innovation will remain important&#x2014;to seed research and development (R&#x0026;D), create a
modern infrastructure backbone and provide public goods. Where markets shut out
promising new activities, denying them access to finance or failing to provide needed
information or infrastructure, government will have a role to play in removing
blockages. There is indeed a sound rationale for government assistance for 
<italic>new</italic>
promising 
<italic>activities</italic> (not sectors), but safeguards will also be needed to avoid
creating lasting distortions or underwriting failures. In preparing government for
these demanding roles, Qatar can draw on lessons from its successful experience with
hydrocarbons.</p>
<p>A number of initiatives that will help to stimulate the country&#x2019;s budding innovation
system are already underway.</p>
<p>Qatar has now committed to directing 2.8% of GDP to support research. A
national R&#x0026;D strategy, prepared by Qatar National Research Fund (QNRF) in
collaboration with stakeholders from the education, government and private
sectors, is now nearing completion and is set for approval in the latter part of
2012. The formative strategy sets out clear aims that are directly linked to
broader national aspirations: to diversify the economy, to expand scientific
knowledge and capabilities, and to improve social outcomes. The principles of
excellence, merit, creativity and inclusiveness (QNRF is not restricted to Qatar
Foundation entities) espoused by QNRF lie at the core of an innovation
culture.</p>
<p>QNRF has also now completed five rounds of research funding through its flagship
National Priorities Research Program. The establishment of well-resourced research
centres in computing, biosciences, and medicine is expected to bear commercial
dividends in the future. Given the lags entailed in completing high-quality research,
validating results and in taking ideas to the market, Qatar Foundation has made a
long-term commitment to these initiatives.</p>
<p>Again, building on and supporting what exists, the Strategy sets targets for other
initiatives that will help to accelerate the transition to a more diverse and innovative
economy.</p>
<p>Located within Qatar Foundation, Qatar Science and Technology Park (QSTP) will
continue to lead the search for new opportunities that are science and technology
based. This centre provides an environment&#x2014;for collaboration among firms&#x2014;that
crosses traditional research boundaries. The goal is to produce innovative solutions to
practical problems and to develop their commercial application. As it also plays a
critical developmental role for small science and technology based ventures, QSTP
seeks to match ideas with aspiring entrepreneurs. It provides funds to facilitate
proof of concept and then assists start-ups through financial and advisory
support.</p>
<p>Already, QSTP is home to a diverse range of initiatives. iHorizons, a Qatar-based
company, has located its R&#x0026;D arm in QSTP. This company is developing innovative
Arabic language software applications and is also collaborating with Italian partners
in the bioinformatics space. A growing number of large multinational corporations
have a presence in QSTP. For example, Exxon-Mobil has established a research
facility focusing on the environment and LNG technologies. Exxon-Mobil&#x2019;s
Qatar-based research and development facility is collaborating with local campuses
throughout Education City to help them plug into its global research network. Other
large international companies that have a presence in QSTP will be an important
channel through which private sector resources are mobilized to support R&#x0026;D and
commercial experimentation.</p>
<p>The Supreme Council of Information and Communications Technology (ICT Qatar)
oversees Qatar&#x2019;s ambitions in terms of ensuring that the country is wired for the 21st
century. ICT Qatar has invested in an advanced broadband backbone that will ensure
that Qatar is a fully networked nation by 2015. ICT Qatar, through its wider
programs, is supporting the creation of a &#x201C;digital society&#x201D;. It is promoting needed
skills development, is working on platforms for the delivering e-services in
government and business and is actively identifying new business opportunities
in ICT. ICT Qatar is also initiating research that aims to realize the full
benefits of ICT for businesses and individuals. In its role as a regulator,
ICT Qatar will promote liberalization of the sector in the broader public
interest.</p>
<p>Other constituents of the broader innovation eco-system will grow organically. The
international campuses at Education City will continue growing. Not only will they
provide a gateway for citizens to top-flight, internationally-accredited degree
programs, but they will also continue to extend their outreach to the wider
community and strengthen their research in areas of relevance to Qatar&#x2019;s economic
and social development. The College of the North Atlantic, Qatar (CNA-Q) will
continue helping the country to build capabilities in health sciences, information
technology, engineering technology and business studies. The Community College of
Qatar (CCQ) will provide technical and liberal arts programs that will be open to
students of all ages.</p>
<p>The fibre that connects innovation systems is as important as its constituent
elements. The Strategy lays emphasis on the importance of institutional
collaborations, which are now beginning to blossom. The Qatar Development Bank
and the Bedaya Center at Silatech are working together to cultivate entrepreneurship
among young Qataris. Enterprise Qatar and ICT Qatar are partnering to build ICT
capabilities and deliver ICT services to the small business sector. The Qatar
Financial Centre Authority and the Qatar Investment Authority have joined
forces to promote the development of a local asset management industry.
Public-private interfaces are also strengthening. One example is the innovative
credit guarantee schemes that are being promoted by Qatar Development
Bank and Enterprise Qatar. These schemes leverage public funds to defray
the significant risks that commercial banks face when they lend to SME
start-ups.</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Glimpsing the future</title>
<p>On the eve of Qatar&#x2019;s independence in 1971 few could have predicted what
was to follow. Qatar&#x2019;s steep economic ascent has set new records on many
levels.</p>
<p>But Qatar is now changing direction, charting a new course towards a society in
which there is better balance and improved harmony among economic, social, human
and environmental outcomes. Given the exhaustible nature of its hydrocarbon
resources, boundaries on opportunities for industrialization, and the imperative of
engaging citizens in productive economic activities, Qatar is wisely looking to
innovation and knowledge as new sources of wealth.</p>
<p>Qatar accepts that the required transformations will take time. Improved economic
management, greater economic efficiency and productivity advances must come first.
A strengthened private sector and a more responsive state are also required.
Adjustments to social policies will be needed to recast incentives in ways that
increase society&#x2019;s demand for and use of knowledge. Greater traction on these issues
will help to amplify and spread the impacts of the bold experiments that Qatar is
taking to support innovation and the development and commercialization of
knowledge. Deeper changes in mindsets and behaviour are no doubt called for, but
these are not fixed. If Qatar can succeed in reshaping incentives, growing the
capabilities of its citizens and expanding their horizons, it will measure up
to the challenges of the new century, creating a durable legacy for future
generations.</p>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Acknowledgements</title>
<p>&#x201C;The authors are grateful to: Mr. Hamad Rashid Al-Mohannadi, Mr. Saad Sherida
Al-Kaabi, and Mr. Ali Hassan Al-Sidiky for sharing their wisdom and valuable
insights on the history and events surrounding Qatar&#x2019;s hydrocarbons&#x2019; industry
development. HE Dr. Saleh Al Nabit, Secretary General of the General Secretariat of
Development Planning provided valuable advice. Excellent technical support was
given by Ms. Fidelis Sadicon.&#x201D;</p>
</sec>
<sec>
<title>Glossary of terms and abbreviations</title>
<p><def-list id="connect201209de1">
<def-item>
<term>b/d </term>
<def>
<p>Barrels per day <!--\itemsep -2pt--></p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>GCC </term>
<def>
<p>Gulf Cooperation Council</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>GDP </term>
<def>
<p>Gross domestic product</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>GSDP </term>
<def>
<p>General Secretariat for Development Planning</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>GTLs </term>
<def>
<p>Gas-to-liquid fuels</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>ICT </term>
<def>
<p>Information and communications technology</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>IMD </term>
<def>
<p>Institute for Management Development</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>IMF </term>
<def>
<p>International Monetary Fund</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>INSEAD </term>
<def>
<p>Institut Europ&#x00E9;en d&#x2019;Administration des Affaires</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>IOCs </term>
<def>
<p>International oil companies</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>LNG </term>
<def>
<p>Liquefied natural gas</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>OECD </term>
<def>
<p>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>PPP </term>
<def>
<p>Public-private partnership</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>PSA </term>
<def>
<p>Production-sharing agreement</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>QAR </term>
<def>
<p>Qatari riyal</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>QAPCO </term>
<def>
<p>Qatar Petrochemical Company</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>QDB </term>
<def>
<p>Qatar Development Bank</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>QSTP </term>
<def>
<p>Qatar Science and Technology Park</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>R&#x0026;D </term>
<def>
<p>Research and development</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>SME </term>
<def>
<p>Small and medium-sized enterprise</p></def></def-item>
<def-item>
<term>SOE </term>
<def>
<p>State-owned enterprise</p></def></def-item> </def-list></p></sec></body>
<back>
<sec>
<title>Notes</title>
<p><fn id="FN3">
<label><sup>1</sup></label>
<p>Qatar National Vision 2030, General Secretariat for Development Planning (2008), GSDP, Doha 
<uri xlink:href="http://www2.gsdp.gov.qa/portal/page/portal/gsdp&#x005F;en/qatar&#x005F;national&#x005F;vision/qnv&#x005F;2030&#x005F;document/QNV2030&#x005F;English&#x005F;v2.pdf">http://www2.gsdp.gov.qa/portal/page/portal/gsdp&#x005F;en/qatar&#x005F;national&#x005F;vision/qnv&#x005F;2030&#x005F;document/QNV2030&#x005F;English&#x005F;v2.pdf</uri>&#x00A0;[Accessed 31 July 2012].</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN4">
<label><sup>2</sup></label>
<p>Qatar National Development Strategy 2011&#x2013;2016, General Secretariat for Development Planning (2011), GSDP, Doha 
<uri xlink:href="http://www2.gsdp.gov.qa/NDS/e&#x005F;book/en/index.html">http://www2.gsdp.gov.qa/NDS/e&#x005F;book/en/index.html</uri>&#x00A0;[Accessed 31 July 2012].</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN5">
<label><sup>3</sup></label>
<p>A technological process of transforming natural gas into its liquid form-liquefied natural gas (LNG).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN6">
<label><sup>4</sup></label>
<p>Doing Business 2012: Doing Business in a More Transparent World, The World Bank, Washington, DC. 
<uri xlink:href="http://publications.worldbank.org/index.php?main&#x005F;page=product&#x005F;info&#x0026;products&#x005F;id=24212">http://publications.worldbank.org/index.php?main&#x005F;page=product&#x005F;info&#x0026;products&#x005F;id=24212</uri>&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN7">
<label><sup>5</sup></label>
<p>The World Competitiveness Scoreboard 2012, IMD, Switzerland. 
<uri xlink:href="http://www.imd.org/research/publications/wcy/World-Competitiveness-Yearbook-Results/#/wcy-2012-rankings/">http://www.imd.org/research/publications/wcy/World-Competitiveness-Yearbook-Results/#/wcy-2012-rankings/</uri>&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN8">
<label><sup>6</sup></label>
<p>The Global Competitiveness Report 2011&#x2013;2012, World Economic Forum, Switzerland 
<uri xlink:href="http://www.weforum.org/reports/global-competitiveness-report-2011-2012">http://www.weforum.org/reports/global-competitiveness-report-2011-2012</uri>&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN9">
<label><sup>7</sup></label>
<p>The Global Innovation Index 2011: Accelerating Growth and Development, INSEAD, Fontainebleau. 
<uri xlink:href="http://www.insead.edu/facultyresearch/research/details&#x005F;books.cfm?id=29390">http://www.insead.edu/facultyresearch/research/details&#x005F;books.cfm?id=29390</uri>&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN10">
<label><sup>8</sup></label>
<p>World Bank Worldwide Governance Indicators database 
<uri xlink:href="http://info.worldbank.org/governance/wgi/index.asp">http://info.worldbank.org/governance/wgi/index.asp</uri><!--\unskip \break -->&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN11">
<label><sup>9</sup></label>
<p>Corruption Perception Index 2011, Transparency International 
<uri xlink:href="http://cpi.transparency.org/cpi2011/results/">http://cpi.transparency.org/cpi2011/results/</uri><!--\unskip \break -->&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN12">
<label><sup>10</sup></label>
<p>Qatar National Development Strategy 2011&#x2013;2016, GSDP, Doha 
<uri xlink:href="http://www2.gsdp.gov.qa/NDS/e&#x005F;book/en/index.html">http://www2.gsdp.gov.qa/NDS/e&#x005F;book/en/index.html</uri>&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN13">
<label><sup>11</sup></label>
<p>Human Development Report 2011, UNDP, New York 
<uri xlink:href="http://hdr.undp.org/en/reports/global/hdr2011/">http://hdr.undp.org/en/reports/global/hdr2011/</uri>&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn> 
<fn id="FN14">
<label><sup>12</sup></label>
<p>Qatar Article IV Report 2011, International Monetary Fund (2012), Washington, DC 
<uri xlink:href="www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/scr/2012/cr1218.pdf">www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/scr/2012/cr1218.pdf</uri>&#x00A0;(Accessed 2 September 2012).</p></fn></p></sec>
<ref-list>
<title>References</title>
<ref id="b1">
<label>[1]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<article-title>Qatar - gas field awaits development<!--~--></article-title>
<x>(</x>
<year>1981</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Petroleum Economist</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>48</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>9</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>375</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>379</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b2">
<label>[2]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Wietfeld</surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>AM</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2011</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Understanding Middle East gas exporting behavior</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Energy Journal</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>32</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>2</issue>
<x>),
</x>
<fpage>203</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>228</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b3">
<label>[3]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<article-title>First cargo of Pearl GTL products ship from Qatar<!--~--></article-title>
<x>(</x>
<year>2011</year>
<x>). </x>
<source>Oil Gas European
Magazine</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>37</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>3</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>116</fpage>
<x>.</x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b4">
<label>[4]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Al-Amoodi</surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Felton</surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>KC</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Kasim</surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>
<x>, </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Whitehead</surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>M</given-names></string-name>
<x>, &#x0026; </x>
<string-name>
<surname>Kouki</surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>K</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2011</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Leveraging a common infrastructure to support Qatar&#x2019;s rapid LNG
expansion</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>SPE Projects, Facilities and Construction</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>6</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>3</issue>
<x>), </x>
<fpage>145</fpage>
<x>&#x2013;</x>
<lpage>154</lpage>
<x>. </x></element-citation></ref>
<ref id="b5">
<label>[5]</label>
<element-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name>
<surname>Forbes</surname>
<x>, </x>
<given-names>A</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>
<x>&#x00A0;</x>
<x>(</x>
<year>2011</year>
<x>). </x>
<article-title>Pearl promises a new dawn for GTL</article-title>
<x>. </x>
<source>Petroleum Economist</source>
<x>, </x>
<volume>78</volume>
<x>(</x>
<issue>2</issue>
<x>), </x>
<comment>2 p.</comment></element-citation></ref>
</ref-list>
</back></article>
