<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Atypon//DTD Atypon Systems Journal Archiving and Interchange NLM DTD v3.0.0 20090430//EN" "atypon-archivearticle3.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="editorial">
<front>
<journal-meta> 
<journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">connect</journal-id> 
<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">connect</journal-id> 
<journal-title-group> 
<journal-title>QScience Connect</journal-title> 
</journal-title-group> 
<issn pub-type="ppub">2223-506X</issn> 
<publisher> 
<publisher-name>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals</publisher-name>
</publisher> 
</journal-meta> 
<article-meta> 
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1</article-id> 
<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5339/connect.2011.1</article-id> 
<article-categories> 
<subj-group subj-group-type="heading"> 
<subject>Editorial</subject> 
</subj-group> 
</article-categories> 
<title-group> 
<article-title>QScience Connect opens up a world of academic research</article-title> 
</title-group> 
<contrib-group>  
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<string-name>
<given-names>Christopher</given-names>
<x> </x>              
<surname>Leonard</surname> </string-name> 
<xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c1"><sup>&#x204E;</sup></xref>               </contrib> 
<aff>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals,
Education City, PO Box 5825, Doha, Qatar</aff></contrib-group>
<author-notes> 
<corresp id="c1"><sup>&#x204E;</sup>cjamesleonard@qf.org.qa</corresp></author-notes> 
<pub-date pub-type="pub"> 
<day>15</day> 
<month>11</month> 
<year>2011</year> </pub-date> 
<issue content-type="issue-sequence">2011</issue> 
<elocation-id>1</elocation-id> 
<history> 
<date date-type="received">
<day>19</day>
<month>10</month>
<year>2011</year></date></history>
<permissions> 
<copyright-statement>&#x00A9;&#x00A0;2011 Leonard,
licensee Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation Journals. This is an open access article
distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License CC BY
3.0 which permits unrestricted use, distribution and reproduction in any medium,
provided the original work is properly cited.</copyright-statement> 
<copyright-year>2011</copyright-year> 
<copyright-holder>Bloomsbury Qatar Foundation
Journals</copyright-holder> </permissions>
<self-uri content-type="pdf" xlink:href="connect.2011.1.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>   
</article-meta>  
</front> 
<body>
<p><!--\noindent -->You are reading what we hope will become an important and, potentially
revolutionary, new academic journal. Not only is it peer-reviewed and open access,
like all QScience.com journals, it is also unique in its scope, as it intends to publish
research in all fields from architecture to zoology. A full list of subject areas can be
found on the journal website.</p>
<p>Our only criteria for acceptance in the journal is that the presented work be original
and has been performed to the standards and practices normal to that field. We do
not ask our reviewers to judge the perceived interest in the work, or the
scale of the advancement. We just check to make sure it is valid, ethical and
correct.</p>
<p>It is more important to us to have the readers determine the interest and usefulness
of an article. Each article shows the number of downloads it has attracted, as well as
allowing readers to leave comments on each article. When an article is cited
by another article, the citing article information is displayed alongside the
original.</p>
<p>Much of the research carried out in today&#x2019;s environments is multidisciplinary in
nature, and we hope that some of this work will find a home in the journal.</p>
<p>We are also extending and developing the concept of an article and will happily
consider audio and video files as manuscripts, provided a text abstract is also
supplied. This is important for fields which may not have previously considered
&#x2018;publishing&#x2019; their work in an academic journal before now.</p>
<p>As with all our journals, abstracts will be translated in Arabic and the author will retain
copyright of their work through a Creative Commons Attribution license (CC BY
3.0)<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN1"><sup>1</sup></xref>
<fn id="FN1">
<label>1</label>
<p><uri xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</uri></p></fn></p>
<p>We hope that this fresh approach to journal publishing will open up a fascinating
world of academic research to our readers.</p> </body></article>
